ʻʻ'ʰʰʸ ʰʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸ.
「ʰʰʸʰʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸʸ」。
ʰʰʰʸʸ.
ʰʰʰʸʸ。
Remind you that this speech is in progress, please wear a mask throughout
このスピーチは進行中であることをお知らせします。スピーチ中は常にマスクを着用してください
And eating and drinking video and audio recording are prohibited
また飲食・動画・録音は禁止です
Do not use the flash when taking pictures
写真を撮るときはフラッシュを使用しないでください
Thank you for your cooperation
ご協力ありがとうございます
In addition, in order to make our activities better, we need your valuable opinions
また、私たちの活動をより良いものにしていくために、皆様の貴重なご意見が必要です
Please help us scan the QR code of the reward provider before leaving the venue
会場を出る前に特典提供者のQRコードをスキャンしてください。
Fill out the online questionnaire
オンラインアンケートに記入してください
After confirming the completed screen to the service desk staff outside the city
市外窓口担当者に完成画面を確認後
Thanks
ありがとう
A nice little courtesy thank you
素敵なちょっとした礼儀、ありがとう
Academia Sinica's 110-year Knowledge Trial
中央研究院の 110 年にわたる知識の試み
Dean Wang Shijie's popular science lecture begins
王世傑学部長の人気科学講義が始まる
Please invite Director Zeng Guoxiang of the Secretariat to host for us
事務局の曽国祥局長を主催者として招待してください。
Family members of Academician Wang, Director Lei's speaker today
本日の雷院長の講演者である王学者の家族
All advanced students present
上級生全員が出席
Good night everyone online
オンラインの皆さんおやすみ
I am Zeng Guoxiang, Director of the Secretariat of the Chinese Academy
私は中国学院事務局長の曽国祥です。
The secretariat is also a series of knowledge experiments
事務局も知識実験シリーズ
The organizer of this lecture by Dean Gu
この講演会の主催者 Dean Gu 氏
Originally this lecture should be given by us
本来この講義は私たちが行うべきものでした
Vice President Wang personally hosted but because
王副総統が自ら主催したが、
In fact, something happened, so please let me host it instead of him.
実は、ちょっとした事があったので、代わりに私に司会をお願いしました。
Then there is a huge difference between my academic second and the associate dean.
それから、私の学術二位と副学部長の間には大きな違いがあります。
It's just that everyone is here today, the important thing is not the host
今日はみんながいるというだけで大事なのは主催者ではない
The most important thing today is of course our keynote speaker
今日最も重要なのは、もちろん基調講演者です
I believe that everyone is also here to admire the name.
皆さんもその名に憧れていらっしゃると思います。
Because the Director of Lei, Mr. Lei Xiangning
なぜなら、レイのディレクター、レイ・シャンニン氏だからです。
He is a very famous and outstanding historian in Taiwan
彼は台湾で非常に有名で傑出した歴史家です
In fact, he graduated from the Chemistry Department of National Taiwan University.
実は彼は国立台湾大学化学科を卒業したのです。
PhD in History of Science from the University of Chicago
シカゴ大学で科学史の博士号を取得
So this is crossing a big boundary
つまり、これは大きな境界線を越えています
Then his research works are very many, very profound.
彼の研究は非常に多く、非常に奥深いものです。
Moreover, his most important works are published by famous foreign university presses.
さらに、彼の最も重要な作品は有名な外国の大学出版局から出版されています。
including his alma mater's prestigious University of Chicago Press
彼の母校である名門シカゴ大学出版局を含む
So today I have the opportunity to give you the opportunity to
そこで今日は皆さんにこの機会を与えることができました。
Gathering together, Mr. Lin Ting's speech I believe is a guarantee for everyone
集まって、リン・ティン氏のスピーチはすべての人にとっての保証であると私は信じています
Very enjoyable evening myself and a lover of reading
私自身と読書愛好家にとってとても楽しい夜です
A man of history is not an expert in history
歴史家は歴史の専門家ではない
Well, what we're going to talk about today is actually very interesting.
さて、今日私たちが話そうとしていることは、実際には非常に興味深いものです。
Because today, of course, in the past two or three years, everyone knows
なぜなら、今日、もちろん過去 2 ～ 3 年で、誰もが知っているからです。
Our lives have been greatly affected by the epidemic
私たちの生活は疫病によって大きな影響を受けています
But in fact, the epidemic has changed human society
しかし実際には、疫病は人間社会を変えました
Of course he didn't die today, everyone probably knows that.
もちろん彼は今日死んだわけではない、それは誰もが知っているだろう。
In fact, for example, in the 1930s there was a very famous
実際、たとえば、1930 年代に非常に有名なことがありました。
This so-called Chinese tuberculosis is a mystery
このいわゆる中国の結核は謎です
Because in fact at the time
というのも、実は当時は
China is not the most industrialized country
中国は最も工業化された国ではない
But the death rate of people in China who suffer from tuberculosis
しかし、結核に苦しむ中国人の死亡率は
four times that of a country like the UK
イギリスのような国の4倍
That sometimes seems like such a mystery
それは時々とても謎に思えるかもしれません
Maybe our on-site factory store is interesting, it's a biomedical institute
おそらく私たちの敷地内の工場ストアは興味深いでしょう、それは生物医学研究所です
This may not be the person who actually made the vaccine
この人は実際にワクチンを製造した人物ではない可能性があります
Questions that can be answered by people who actually do medical treatment
実際に医療を行っている人だからこそ答えられる疑問
This is through history
これは歴史を通じて
Through historians' re-combating in the beginning
初期の歴史家の再戦闘を通じて
Come and tell us to solve this very interesting mystery
この非常に興味深い謎を解決するために来てください。
and then through this question
そしてこの質問を通して
can make us reflect
私たちに反省させることができる
Today, we are also living with this era of vaccines.
今日、私たちはワクチンの時代にも生きています。
How do we get from vaccines
ワクチンからどうやって感染するのか
Then reflect on ourselves from this disease
それからこの病気で苦しんだ自分たちを振り返ってください
Relationships with people, society, and society
人・社会・社会との関わり
And then go on to allow ourselves to understand the history of infectious diseases on our bodies
そして、私たちの体に起こった感染症の歴史を理解できるようにしていきましょう
have a richer understanding
より豊かな理解を得る
And then to our own times
そして私たちの時代へ
Especially civilized, East Asian, these issues of modernity
特に文明的、東アジア、現代の問題
have a chance to reflect
反省する機会がある
then today we will
それでは今日はそうします
Wait a minute and I can invite this teacher to give a speech
ちょっと待ってください。この先生を講演に招待します
In the end, everyone can probably tell from the beginning.
結局のところ、誰でも最初からわかるはずです。
Also, he was talking about a vaccine
ワクチンについても話していました
no immediate relationship
直接の関係はありません
i think we have dinner today
今日は夕食だと思います
This Chinese dining table has a rotating table
この中華ダイニングテーブルには回転テーブルが付いています
His birth through this revolving table
この回転テーブルを通して彼の誕生
What I want to tell us is exactly the mystery I left just now.
私が伝えたいのは、まさに今残した謎です。
It is China's understanding and fame
それは中国の理解と名声です
As for the detailed reasons
詳しい理由としては
Shall we give Mr. Lei a big round of applause?
レイさんに盛大な拍手を送りましょうか？
come and speak for us
来て私たちのために話してください
thank you thank you everyone
ありがとう、みんなありがとう
my mic is on
私のマイクはオンになっています
open?
開ける？
both are open
どちらも開いています
The back seems to be open
背中が開いているように見える
That's good
それは良い
good
良い
Thank you very much for the introduction of Yimei, the head of Pearl
パール代表のイーメイさんのご紹介、誠にありがとうございます。
very honored
とても光栄です
then i feel very honored
それならとても光栄に思います
I had the opportunity to do this with you here today
今日はここで皆さんと一緒にこれを行う機会がありました
Lecture by Dean Wang Shijie of Academia Sinica
中央研究院 王世潔研究科長による講演
Especially this relative of President Wang is here
特にこの王総統の親戚はここにいる
Because it was actually last year that I had the chance
チャンスがあったのは実は去年だったので
Until that is to say, the European and American office opposite the technical office
それまでは、技術事務所の向かいにある欧米事務所
that beautiful building
あの美しい建物
It was designed by Ms. Wang Qinghua, the daughter of President Wang.
設計したのは王総統の娘、王清華さん。
just know a lot of his stories
彼の話はたくさんしか知らない
So it's a double honor
それは二重の名誉です
I am very glad to have the opportunity to do this report with you.
このようなレポートをご一緒させていただく機会をいただけたことを大変うれしく思っております。
So hello friends here and friends online
こんにちは、ここにいる友達、そしてオンラインの友達
That's the topic I want to talk about today
それが今日話したいテーマです
I want to say that when you see it, you don’t know how it feels
見たらどんな感じになるか分からないって言いたい
should come to mind right away
すぐに思い浮かぶはずです
What is a Chinese revolving table
中国の回転テーブルとは
mask good thanks
マスクいいですね、ありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
That is, let me start with our topic and introduce to you
つまり、私たちのトピックから始めて、それを紹介しましょう。
The main axis that I will talk about today
今日お話しする主軸
First of all, we are all so familiar that it may be difficult for us to imagine
まず第一に、私たちは皆、あまりにもよく知っているので、想像するのが難しいかもしれません。
Foreigners in this picture will be very surprised to find
この写真に写っている外国人はとても驚くでしょう
There's something on this table they've never seen
このテーブルには彼らが見たことのない何かがある
a piece of furniture
一個家具
It's the revolving table we just talked about
それは先ほど話した回転テーブルです
Then this is a very familiar thing to us
それから、これは私たちにとって非常に身近なものです。
So I think it might be hard for you to imagine saying
だから、こう言うのは想像しにくいかもしれないと思います
In fact, before the 20th century, on the Chinese dining table
実は20世紀以前、中国の食卓では
Such a convenient piece of furniture does not exist
こんな便利な家具は存在しない
This is actually a new invention to the 20th century
実はこれは20世紀の新しい発明なのです
right
右
and then the second
そして二番目
Japan and Korea who also use chopsticks
箸も使う日本と韓国
We can't see the carousel either
カルーセルも見えません
Unless you go to his Chinese restaurant
彼の中華レストランに行かなければ
In fact, the Japanese think
実は日本人はこう考えている
This is what they invented
これは彼らが発明したものです
that's a
それは
Be independent of me for stories other than today's story
今日の話以外は独立してください
If you are interested, I will talk to you later
興味があれば、後でお話します
that's the second place
それは2位です
may surprise everyone
みんなを驚かせるかもしれない
The third point is
3つ目のポイントは、
It's not just a simple piece of furniture
ただのシンプルな家具ではありません
when it was invented
それが発明されたとき
is closely related to public health
公衆衛生と密接に関係している
even has an english name
英語の名前もあります
It's called Hygienic Chinese Dining Table
その名も「衛生中華食卓」
A Chinese sanitary dining table
中国の衛生的な食卓
So it has something to do with our current epidemic situation.
つまり、それは現在の感染症の状況と関係があるのです。
And what?
そして何？
Its inventor was in fact
その発明者は実は
Many people know today
今日では知っている人も多いでしょう
Dr. Wu Liande
ウー・リアンデ博士
He is the Chinese
彼は中国人です
Citizens in British Malaya
英領マラヤの国民
A Doctor of Medicine from Jianqiao University
建橋大学医学博士
is that
それは？
And it's important
そしてそれは重要です
He is recognized for his research
彼はその研究で認められている
In 1935, he received the Liu Beier medical certificate
1935年、彼はリュー・バイエルの診断書を受け取った。
nomination for a scholarship
奨学金の推薦
So should be the first to be nominated
だから最初に指名されるはずだ
A person of Chinese descent who won the Nobel Prize in Medicine
ノーベル医学賞を受賞した中国系の人
now about him
今、彼のことについて
he's become very very famous now
彼は今ではとてもとても有名になりました
partly because
部分的には
After the discovery of the COVID outbreak
新型コロナウイルス感染症の流行が判明してから
everyone thinks
誰もが思う
The inventor of the anti-epidemic mask we wear today
私たちが現在着用している防疫マスクの発明者
maybe it's him
たぶんそれは彼です
In fact, most of our inventions have previous
実際、私たちの発明のほとんどは以前に
previous story
前の話
It's hard to say who invented
誰が発明したのか言うのは難しい
But now if you go to Google
しかし今、Google にアクセスすると、
Go check CAN
CANをチェックしてみよう
some mainstream media
一部の主流メディア
will say
言うだろう
This is the time when the Manchurian plague was fought five years ago
これは5年前に満州の疫病と闘った時です
From 1910 to 1911
1910年から1911年まで
invented this
これを発明した
It is the first pioneer in the use of anti-epidemic masks by humans
人間による防疫マスクの使用の最初の先駆者です。
So he's now become this international celebrity
それで彼は今ではこの国際的な有名人になりました
When I first started researching him
私が最初に彼のことを調べ始めたとき
In fact, it was the situation when SARS was over.
実際、SARSが終息したときもそうでした。
that is such a person
それはそのような人です
so think about it
だからそれについて考えてください
It's actually an interesting story
実は面白い話なんです
One we use everyday at home
我が家で毎日使っているもの
we even thought
私たちも思った
It may have been used for hundreds of thousands of years
何十万年も使われてきた可能性がある
very convenient piece of furniture
とても便利な家具
It actually had to wait until the 20th century for it to be invented
実際に発明されるまでには 20 世紀まで待たなければなりませんでした
and still a
そしてまだ
Invented by Nobel-Lectured Scientists
ノーベル賞を受賞した科学者によって発明された
Think about it, if we now know
考えてみましょう、今わかっているのなら
that our current dean
私たちの現在の学部長が
Or the former vice president of Jianren
あるいは建連の元副会長か
He actually designed it for us
彼は実際に私たちのためにそれをデザインしてくれました
an item on our dinner table at home
我が家の食卓にある一品
Everyone must be surprised, right?
誰もが驚くはずですよね？
So inside this shadow
だからこの影の中で
In fact, it implies that
実際、それは次のことを意味します
During our epidemic prevention process
伝染病予防プロセス中
In fact, some of them are very deep
実際、それらの中には非常に奥深いものもあります
into our daily life
私たちの日常生活の中に
and then become our
そして私たちのものになる
part of life
人生の一部
so my today
だから私の今日
at that time
その時
When Wuliande designed
五蓮徳が設計したとき
is to solve a
を解決することです
The most important cause of death in China at that time
当時の中国の最も重要な死因
It's what Director Zeng mentioned just now.
それは今曽所長がおっしゃったことです。
It's Fei Jie and
フェイ・ジエです
so there's a very serious reason
とても深刻な理由があります
and this
この
This photo and this article
この写真とこの記事
on board
機内で
The National Medical Journal of China 的
中国国家医学雑誌
The first issue of the first issue in 1915
1915年創刊
As far as today's so-called Chinese Medical Journal
今日のいわゆる中国医学雑誌を見る限り、
So you read an English medical journal
それであなたは英語の医学雑誌を読みました
The first issue of the inaugural issue published a photo
創刊号には写真が掲載されました
Then to address the most important cause of death
次に、最も重要な死因に対処するために
But there is indeed one that none of us know today
しかし、今日私たちの誰も知らないものが確かにあります
Furniture Invented in Taipei in the Second Century
2世紀に台北で発明された家具
So this is what I want to tell you today
そこで今日お伝えしたいのはこれです
So I want to share with you through this story
そこで、この物語を通して皆さんと共有したいと思います
some bigger questions
いくつかの大きな質問
So if the simplest speech
したがって、最も単純なスピーチであれば、
China is a very simple story
中国というのは非常に単純な話だ
That is why the prevention and control of infectious diseases will promote
だからこそ、感染症の予防と制御が推進されます。
Nobel-Lecture Physician
ノーベル講師の医師
Design a brand new daily necessities?
新しい日用品をデザインしてみませんか？
like i just said
先ほど言ったように
if we want now
今すぐ望むなら
that our dean
私たちの学部長が
Help us design supplies for our home
家庭用品のデザインにご協力ください
Everyone should be surprised, right?
誰もが驚くはずですよね？
But I'm in the process of solving this mystery
しかし、私はこの謎を解き明かしている途中です
Actually what I want to say is
実は私が言いたいのは、
we prevent the epidemic
私たちは流行を防ぎます
In fact, everyone should feel
実は誰もが感じているはず
How much our lives have changed in the past two years
過去 2 年間で私たちの生活はどれだけ変化したか
after two years
2年後
The whole world is different, right?
世界全体が違いますよね？
But the story I want to tell today is
でも、今日私が話したい話は、
In addition to the many changes we know
私たちが知っている多くの変更に加えて、
and some more
そしてさらにいくつか
deep change
深い変化
we may not realize so easily
私たちはそう簡単には気づかないかもしれない
There is a series of changes initiated
一連の変化が始まっています
The anti-epidemic measures developed to combat infectious diseases
感染症と戦うために開発された防疫対策
How has prompted a series of new developments
一連の新たな展開をどのように促したか
We may not often think of
私たちはあまり考えないかもしれませんが、
Contains the new living appliances of our life
私たちの生活に欠かせない新しい生活家電が入っています
Awareness and feelings of a new body
新しい身体への気づきと感覚
change in your body
あなたの体の変化
The sense of body has also changed
身体の感覚も変わりました
and your habit change
そしてあなたの習慣が変わります
Sanitation habits have changed
衛生習慣が変わった
The habit of speaking English is your second nature
英語を話す習慣はあなたの第二の天性です
right
右
You have changed in a profound sense
あなたは深い意味で変わりました
Even the relevant ethical values ​​have changed
関連する倫理的価値観さえも変化した
and my generals and
そして私の将軍たちと
Relationships and general boundaries have also changed
人間関係や一般的な境界線も変化した
That's my topic at the end
それが最後の私のトピックです
Finally
ついに
Individual and group self-identities are also altered
個人および集団の自己アイデンティティも変化する
so i think
だから私は思う
I often pass this one
よくここを通ります
A specific story about the Chinese rotating ginseng pan
中国の回転高麗人参鍋に関する具体的なストーリー
Then we see every day may not know
それなら私たちは毎日見ても分からないかもしれない
we have a history of this history
私たちにはこの歴史があります
to make everyone feel
みんなに感じてもらうために
We are in the process of epidemic prevention
私たちは疫病予防の真っ最中です
What profound changes have been caused
なんて深い変化なんだろう
There are so many facets
とてもたくさんの側面があります
And what?
そして何？
These aspects are often not legal
これらの側面は多くの場合合法ではありません
not by thought
思考によるものではなく
but in an instrumental or bodily way
しかし、手段的または身体的な方法で
changed us
私たちを変えた
become a part of us
私たちの一部になる
In the end it means
結局それが意味するのは
If everyone thinks you're surprised too
みんなが思ったら君も驚いてるよ
This thing is actually a
これは実際には
If medical experts found out on a Japanese TV station
日本のテレビ局で医療専門家が知ったら
It provides a very important clue that
それは非常に重要な手がかりを提供します
It is because we all think of epidemic prevention as
それは、誰もが防疫を次のように考えているからです。
just to prevent contagion
感染を防ぐためだけに
and just help us to be healthy
そして私たちが健康になるのを手伝ってください
we think of it as a tool
私たちはそれをツールとして考えています
So we didn't realize the change
だから私たちは変化に気づかなかった
is a comprehensive cultural change
包括的な文化の変化です
And implement it in our body
そしてそれを私たちの体に実装します
so we often
だから私たちはよく
didn't realize the change
変化に気づかなかった
changing presence
変化する存在感
That's a hidden history
それは隠された歴史だ
That's one I want to share with you today
今日はそれを皆さんと共有したいと思います
one
一個
behind a big background
背後的一個大的背景
Of course one of them
もちろんそのうちの1つ
I hope we
私たちがそう願っています
That is to say, when everyone listens to such a story
つまり、そういう話をみんなが聞くと、
also feel that
それも感じます
Some epidemic prevention measures we usually think about
私たちが普段考えている伝染病予防策
In fact, the impact on us
実際、私たちに与える影響は、
maybe more than we thought
おそらく私たちが思っていた以上に
There are many far-reaching
遠大なものもたくさんあります
that's the one behind me
それは私の後ろにいる人です
big idea
大きなアイデア
OK, so let's start talking about this now.
さて、それでは今から話しましょう。
Why is his tuberculosis problem
なぜ彼は結核を患っているのか
He will think about this place
彼はこの場所について考えるでしょう
This is a Japanese book
これは日本の本です
First published in 1914 as Tuberculosis and Digestion
1914 年に『結核と消化』として初出版
Diagram of the spreading system of fine infectious diseases
微細感染症の蔓延システム図
Then he talks about bubble contagion
それから彼はバブルの伝染について話します
That should be what we call today
それは今日私たちがそう呼ぶべきものです
Droplet infection, right?
飛沫感染ですよね？
Then here we see a person
それからここに人が見えます
Then this person is actually a
じゃあこの人は実は
tuberculosis patients
肺結核的患者
He already consciously wants to cover his mouth with his hand
彼はすでに意識的に手で口を覆いたくなっています
but this drool
しかしこのよだれ
Then this picture may not be clear enough.
それでは、この写真では十分に鮮明ではないかもしれません。
They are actually red dots
実際には赤い点です
start cumming on this guy
この男に射精を開始します
So what am I talking about now?
それで、私は今何を話しているのでしょうか？
this is the nineteenth century
これは19世紀です
very brilliant one
とても素晴らしいもの
low blood breakthrough
低血液突破
to the bacteria
細菌に
The discovery of germ theory
細菌理論の発見
Then I get from this
それから私はこれから得ます
We're all too familiar with this now
私たちは今、このことをよく知っています
So it may be difficult for everyone to imagine the feeling
なので、皆さんにはその気持ちを想像するのは難しいかもしれませんが、
The sense of breakthrough
突破口の感覚
just suddenly you feel
突然あなたはそう感じます
where you can't see
見えないところ
full of things that can make you sick
病気になる可能性のあるものがいっぱいです
sick germs, right?
病気の細菌ですよね？
then the danger is everywhere
そうすれば危険はどこにでもある
This is a
これは
Such a huge change in worldview
こんなに世界観が大きく変わるなんて
so all of a sudden
それで突然
Experts all over the world are busy doing it
世界中の専門家がその作業に忙しい
Tell the public with various images
さまざまなイメージで世間に伝える
In fact, there are all kinds of dangers around you.
実際、あなたの周りにはあらゆる種類の危険が存在します。
It's sprayed out here where you can't see it
見えないところに噴き出してます
All that comes out are red dots
出てくるのは赤い点だけ
brings countless dangers
数え切れないほどの危険をもたらす
then you should feel a sense of dread
そうすればあなたは恐怖を感じるはずです
Then look at this cup over here
それから、ここにあるこのカップを見てください
It's also a red dot, right?
それも赤点ですよね？
so after this
それでこの後
when you use someone else's cup
他人のカップを使用するとき
It's completely different from before
以前とは全く違います
You'll feel like you're full of this germ
この菌でお腹がいっぱいになったような気分になるでしょう
There are a lot of pictures showing you where it will happen
どこで何が起こるかを示す図がたくさんあります
For example, before people would
たとえば、人々がそうする前に、
That's not the one that flips the book, right?
それは本をひっくり返すものではありませんよね？
Now you also think it might be a germ
今、あなたもそれは細菌かもしれないと考えています
even like us or that
私たちやあれのようにさえ
It turns out that grandparents chewed up food and gave it to children
祖父母が食べ物を噛み砕いて子供たちに与えていたことが判明
Now you think it's spreading germs too
今、あなたはそれが細菌も広めていると思います
Even men's beards were shaved later
男性のひげも後で剃られるようになった
Because I think your beard is easy to hide germs
あなたのひげは細菌を隠しやすいと思うから
And the equipment in our home has changed too.
そして我が家の設備も変わりました。
In the past, there were a lot of designs that were easy to accumulate dust, right?
昔はホコリがたまりやすいデザインが多かったですよね？
Now you think there's germs hiding there
今、あなたはそこに細菌が隠れていると思います
So in fact, learning from the novelty of this germ theory
実際、この細菌理論の新規性から学ぶと、
It's just that people's lives have changed a lot
ただ人々の生活は大きく変わった
And one very important point
そして、非常に重要なポイントが 1 つあります
Is actually the concept of bacterial infection itself
実は細菌感染症そのものの概念である
is a major breakthrough in human thought
それは人間の思考における大きな進歩です
Because of course it wasn't until the nineteenth century that we had infectious diseases
なぜなら、感染症が存在するようになったのはもちろん 19 世紀になってからです。
We've all heard of the Black Death, haven't we?
私たちは皆、黒死病について聞いたことがあるでしょう?
So then the Black Death is said to have killed one-third of Europe's population at that time
それで、黒死病は当時のヨーロッパの人口の3分の1を殺したと言われています
So people have known for a long time that there will be some diseases
したがって、人々は長い間、いくつかの病気が存在することを知っていました
when it suddenly became popular
急に流行ったとき
Many people experience the same symptoms
多くの人が同じ症状を経験しています
mass death
大量死
but the point is
しかし、ポイントは
before the breakthrough of germ theory
細菌理論のブレイクスルー以前
We think of people of this magnitude
私たちはこのような規模の人々のことを考えています
died of the same disease
同じ病気で亡くなった
This spotlight phenomenon
このスポットライト現象
people will think that it must be
人々はそうに違いないと思うだろう
The power of concentrating light causes the phenomenon of concentrating light
光を集める力が光を集める現象を引き起こす
So what is the power of focus?
では、集中力とは何でしょうか？
for example
例えば
if say yes
はいと言えば
brand new tree
真新しい木
it could be cosmic influence
それは宇宙の影響かもしれない
Of course the place speaks
もちろんその場所が語る
climate change
気候変動
Or let's talk about burial devices, right?
あるいは、埋葬装置について話しましょう。
As a result of the environment where there is a burial vessel in this place
この場所に埋葬器がある環境の影響で
or say you say yes
または、あなたが「はい」と言うと言う
Like we talk about warming the mind, right?
心を温めることについて話しているようにね？
is the power of gods and ghosts
それは神と幽霊の力です
just forget to imagine such a
そんな想像するのを忘れてください
When a large-scale epidemic spreads rapidly
大規模な病気が急速に蔓延した場合
you will think so
あなたはそう思うでしょう
Must be the power of light
きっと光の力でしょう
cause spotlight
スポットライトを浴びる原因となる
But after the germ theory happened,
しかし細菌学の後は
we just started
私たちは始めたばかりです
able to imagine
想像できる
It's not happening with spotlight power
スポットライトの力では起こらない
this is one
これは 1 つです
one person to one person one person to one person
1人対1人 1人対1人
spread rapidly
急速に広まった
You couldn't imagine before
以前は想像できなかったでしょう
The power of one person is passed on one by one
このような力は人から人へ受​​け継がれていくものです
Can suddenly spread to many people
突然多くの人に広がる可能性がある
So what I want to say is
それで私が言いたいのは、
the discovery of animalism itself
動物主義そのものの発見
It also constitutes a breakthrough point in our human thinking
それは人間の思考におけるブレークスルーポイントでもあります
Feeling passed from person to person
人から人へ伝わる気持ち
Then it is possible to become a co-optic phenomenon
そうすれば共光学現象になる可能性がある
What is the simplest example of this
これの最も単純な例は何ですか
One of the most familiar
今では最も馴染みのあるもの
This method of spreading is actually computer poisoning
この拡散方法は実際にはコンピュータポイズニングです
right
右
When one is poisoned, you can also be poisoned by millions
一人が毒を受けると、何百万もの人が毒を受ける可能性があります
How would you describe it when it was poisoned?
毒が盛られたときのことをどう表現しますか？
It's about viral infection, right?
ウイルス感染の話ですよね？
So the other way around is to say
逆に言うと、
This breakthrough model of viral and bacterial infection
ウイルスおよび細菌感染の画期的なモデル
becomes a model for our understanding of an other infection
他の感染症を理解するためのモデルとなる
Because before that people can't imagine
それ以前には人々は想像できないからです
contagion like this is possible
このような伝染の可能性があります
So what I'm telling you now is that
だから私が今あなたに言いたいのは、
This whole breakthrough has to do with germ theory
この画期的な進歩はすべて細菌理論に関係しています
it represents a new
それは新しいことを表します
one thinking about things
物事について考えている人
A whole new way of thinking about things
物事についてのまったく新しい考え方
that also has elements we are familiar with
私たちがよく知っている要素も含まれています
talk like here
ここのように話します
you want to talk to this patient
この患者と話したいですか
To maintain a relationship of more than three feet
3フィート以上の関係を維持するには
or you will be infected
そうしないと感染してしまいます
So you have to maintain a social distance
だから社会的距離を保つ必要がある
That is in such a context
そういう文脈の中でですね
just happened
ちょうど今起こった
Let's start thinking about what we're talking about
何について話しているのか考えてみましょう
The Syndrome Problem
症候群の問題
But despite this breakthrough in bacteriology
しかし、この細菌学の進歩にも関わらず、
We just learned that bacterial contagion is conceivable
細菌感染が考えられることを知りました
However, a later discovery was that
ところが、その後に判明したのは、
when you actually check
実際に確認すると
just to test later
後でテストするためだけに
most people have germs
ほとんどの人は細菌を持っています
Most people have tuberculosis
ほとんどの人が結核に罹患している
in that era
あの時代に
just someone having a seizure
ただ誰かが発作を起こしているだけ
Someone didn't have a seizure
発作を起こしていない人もいる
In fact, from this point of view
実際、この観点から見ると、
There is no reason why the person is sick
その人が病気になる理由はない
It's not that he hasn't been exposed to the combined strain.
彼が複合的な緊張にさらされなかったわけではない
but to say
しかし言うこと
but other reasons
しかし他の理由
sorry i skipped a paragraph
ごめんなさい、段落を飛ばしました
I'll jump back and forth to talk about this passage
この一節について話したいと思います
So the bacteria theory just now
それで、今の細菌理論は
The popularity of this concept
コンセプトの人気
cause a lot of anxiety
多くの不安を引き起こす
a very famous anxiety
非常に有名な不安
I'm here to tell you
私はあなたに伝えるためにここにいます
it's about christianity
それはキリスト教についてです
The Common Chalice Controversy
よくある聖杯論争
It's just that everyone knows
それは誰もが知っていることです
When Christians receive the Holy Communion
クリスチャンが聖体拝領を受けるとき
Why don't you just go up and drink in the same glass?
上がって同じグラスで飲んでみませんか？
right
右
This is the insurance of Jesus Christ
これはイエス・キリストの保険です
to all the zune brothers
ズーン兄弟のみんなへ
Everyone also receives the insurance of Jesus Christ
誰もがイエス・キリストの保険を受けます
Then prove that you guys are brothers of Zune
それならあなたたちが Zune の兄弟であることを証明してください
But what?
でも何？
Now you just learned that fine pregnancy
今、あなたは素晴らしい妊娠を学んだばかりです
Is there supposed to be on this cup?
このカップの上にあるはずですか？
Red dot, right?
赤い点ですよね？
Then you see a man ahead
すると前方に男性が見えます
when you keep coughing
咳が続くとき
You start to suspect this Zoney brother
あなたはこのゾーニー兄弟を疑い始めます
In fact, it will bring a big
実際、それは大きなものをもたらすでしょう
dangerous
危険
but if you don't drink because of it
でも、そのせいで飲まなかったら
Wouldn't that be a clear violation
それは明らかな違反ではないでしょうか
Are the Zone brothers thinking right?
ゾーン兄弟の考えは正しいのでしょうか？
That is to say you are so out of touch
つまり、あなたはあまりにも連絡が取れていないということです
Make the people around you suspicious like this
こうやって周りの人を疑ってしまう
he may be your relative
彼はあなたの親戚かもしれません
So this is after you invented the fine pregnancy theory
これはあなたが素晴らしい妊娠理論を発明した後の話ですね
It caused a very big debate in the United States
アメリカで非常に大きな議論を巻き起こした
Should we reform this
これを改革したほうがいいでしょうか
A reform seems to destroy an original symbolic meaning, right?
改革は本来の象徴的な意味を破壊するように思えますよね？
mutual acceptance
相互承認
A ceremony of receiving insurance from the same cup
同杯から保険を受け取る儀式
but in the end
しかし、最後には
By 1898
1898年までに
Two-thirds of U.S. dioceses vote to decide
米国教区の3分の2が投票で決定する
give up this chalice
この聖杯を手放す
can't use this cup anymore
このカップはもう使えません
then change to
次に、に変更します
change it to this
これに変更します
Everyone has a small cup for everyone
誰もが自分用の小さなカップを持っています
Everyone go up and get a glass
みんな上がってグラスを取りなさい
So you can see from this place that means
この場所からわかることは、つまり
After the general popularity of drama theory at that time
当時の演劇理論の一般的な流行の後
People are very concerned about sharing a cup with others
人々は他の人とカップを共有することを非常に心配しています
share your drool
よだれを共有する
An unprecedented sense of fear
今までにない恐怖感
even willing to pay such a high price
そんな高い代償を払う気さえある
destroy one of his symbolic meanings
彼の象徴的な意味の一つを破壊する
you have to change it
それを変えなければなりません
then i just
それから私はちょうど
I just mentioned the next one from here
ここから次のことについて言及しました
says
言う
So everyone thought
そこでみんなが思ったのが
Syndrome is clearly an infectious disease.
症候群は明らかに感染症です。
but then it was
しかし、その時はそうでした
It turns out that almost everyone actually has combined bacteria
ほぼ全員が実際に複合細菌を持っていることが判明
Someone wants to get over it and then it's okay
誰かがそれを乗り越えたいと思っているなら、大丈夫です
So it's obvious that
したがって、それは明らかです
This cannot be explained only by bacteria
細菌だけでは説明できない
So wait until that development from what we just talked about
だから、今話したことから発展するまで待ってください
By the time of the end of the nineteenth century
19世紀の終わりまでに
people will think that in fact
人々は実際にそう思うだろう
Whether you are sick or not
病気であってもなくても
The key factor is not tuberculosis infection
重要な要因は結核感染ではない
but other issues
しかし他の問題
what is it like
それはどんな感じですか
like urbanization and industrialization
都市化や工業化のように
Ventilation and lighting, malnutrition, working hours, etc.
換気や照明、栄養失調、労働時間など。
that is, the very poor
つまり、非常に貧しい人たちです
forced to live in terrible conditions
ひどい環境での生活を強いられる
malnourished very poor
栄養失調で非常に貧しい
they have poor resistance
彼らは抵抗力が弱い
So they have to combine bacteria
そこで細菌を組み合わせる必要がある
So here's a classic in the history of medicine
ここに医学史上の古典があります
叫The Making of a Social Disease
「社会病の成り立ち」
is the first to be considered
最初に考慮されるのは
diseases caused by social factors
社会的要因によって引き起こされる病気
is what we would have thought to say
それは私たちが言おうと思っていたことです
This Non-Combined Is an Infectious Disease
この不結合は感染症です
But now I realize
でも今気づいた
Actually you don't have to fully focus there
実際にはそこに完全に集中する必要はありません
It is very important to say that your life
自分の人生をこう言うことはとても重要です
Is it the one that has enough nutrients
栄養が足りているものなのでしょうか？
If the environment it lives in is well ventilated and well lit
風通しが良く、明るい環境であれば、
In fact, it is not easy to be infected
実は簡単には感染しない
There is also the issue of working hours
労働時間の問題もあるし
So the disease becomes a
したがって、病気は次のようになります。
Instead, we have a turning point
その代わりに転換点が訪れる
What we learned is that
私たちが学んだことは、
state intervention
国家介入
For example, what we are talking about later
たとえば、今話していることは、
work eight hours
8時間働く
also related to this
これにも関係する
It's also related to this
これにも関係してるんですが
And very strong like this picture you see
そしてこの写真のようにとても強いです
It talks about making of social disease
社会病の作り方について語る
I think those who are sick are actually poor
病気の人は実は貧しい人だと思う
They were forced to live in an industrial environment
彼らは工業環境での生活を余儀なくされた
live in a crowded one
混雑した場所に住む
Places with poor ventilation and lighting
風通しや照明の悪い場所
and that is to say bear
つまりクマです
long hours of work
長時間労働
That's why I'm sick
だから私は病気なの
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
To solve the core problem of the disease
病気の中核問題を解決するには
not to keep it from touching germs
雑菌に触れないようにするため
It's about improving its living conditions
それは生活条件を改善することです
Especially give it enough nutrition and so on
特に栄養などを十分に与えてください
On the contrary, do you think that if you are a farmer
逆に、あなたが農家ならこう思いますか？
or those who live in the suburbs
もしくは郊外にお住まいの方
They don't actually get that much
彼らは実際にはそれほど多くを得ていない
Not so easy to get tuberculosis
結核にはかかりにくい
And because of this, when he was recuperating from tuberculosis
このため、彼が結核から療養していたとき、
Often go to the mountains or the sea to recuperate
山や海によく行って療養する
So the story I just told was
それで、私が今話した話は、
Bacteriology
細菌学
But then tuberculosis has
しかしその後、結核が
Tuberculosis has been understood as a disease
結核は病気として理解されている
That is why this disease has become
だからこそこの病気はこうなった
Does the country improve
国は良くなるのか
The living environment of ordinary people is closely related to
一般の人々の生活環境は密接に関係しています。
like Japan
比如像日本
He was originally unwilling to solve this problem by the country.
彼はもともとこの問題を国が解決することに消極的だった。
Later, after the rise of communism
その後、共産主義が台頭すると、
As far as the Japanese government thinks
日本政府が考える限り
must help
助けなければなりません
people improve his workers
人々は従業員を向上させる
Especially the worker improves his living environment
特に労働者は生活環境を改善する
Otherwise such a question
そうでなければそのような質問
would become a hotbed of communism
共産主義の温床になるだろう
That's the background of such a story
そういう物語の背景があったんですね
Then everyone can think of saying
そうすれば誰もがこう言うことを思いつくでしょう
If from this point of view
この観点から言えば
The second day of the 1924 season
1924 シーズンの 2 日目
China is definitely not an industrialized
中国は決して工業国ではない
Or a very highly urbanized country, right?
あるいは非常に都市化が進んだ国ですよね？
At that time it was said that more than 85% were farmers
当時は85％以上が農家だったと言われています。
So logically speaking
論理的に言えば
He shouldn't have that much of a FJH problem.
彼はFJHの問題をそれほど抱えていないはずだ。
In fact, in the 19th century
実は19世紀には
Quite a lot of this missionary classroom in China also said
中国のこの宣教師教室のかなりの数もこう言った
The Chinese don't look like Fei Jiehe's problem is too serious
中国人は費継和の問題がそれほど深刻ではないようだ
there is such a saying
そんな諺があります
But then waited until after the 20th century
しかしその後は20世紀が終わるまで待った
they feel
彼らは感じます
The problem of infectious diseases in China cannot be serious
中国の感染症問題は深刻ではない
Because I think they have a lot of bad habits
彼らには悪い習慣がたくさんあると思うから
That even later China's own Anti-aging Association
その後も中国独自の抗老化協会が設立される
That is, Fei Jiehe was once translated as labor sickness
つまり、費潔和はかつて労働病と訳されていました。
So it's the Anti-Age Society
それがアンチエイジ社会です
They also use some statistics and estimates
また、いくつかの統計と推定も使用します。
And to describe China as a Feijiehe problem
そして中国を飛街河問題として説明する
very serious country
非常に深刻な国
then he said
それから彼は言いました
Combined disease is the deadliest disease in China
複合病は中国で最も致死率の高い病気である
Then China is affected by the combined disease all over the world
その後、中国は世界中で複合的な病気の影響を受ける
deepest cleansing country
最も深い浄化の国
green and original
緑とオリジナル
underground tuberculosis patients
地下結核患者
And then the death rate is at least four times higher than in the UK
そして死亡率は英国より少なくとも4倍高い
is to create an image that is
というイメージを作ることです
this problem is very serious
この問題は非常に深刻です
Even more serious than some industrialized countries
一部の先進国よりもさらに深刻
Even if you have heard
聞いたことがあるとしても
China is the sick man of East Asia
中国は東アジアの病人だ
The imaginary disease should be tuberculosis
想像上の病気は結核でなければなりません
So from our point of view
したがって、私たちの観点からすると、
This should be a pretty strange thing
これはかなり奇妙なことになるはずです
You are obviously a basically agricultural country
あなたは明らかに基本的に農業国です
why you got one
なぜそれを手に入れたのか
In fact, if we look at the nineteenth century
実際、19世紀を見てみると、
For example, about tuberculosis in Japan
たとえば、日本の結核について
It actually said it was low at the beginning
実は最初は低いって言ってた
It is because it rose after industrialization
工業化してから上がったから
Then change after rising
そして上がってから着替える
Only if there are worker sanitation workers will they drop again
衛生管理従事者がいる場合にのみ、再び減少します
Logically speaking, you should be post-industrialized
論理的に言えば、脱工業化されるべきです
You are the only one affected by this disease
この病気に罹患しているのはあなただけです
But at the time these
しかし当時これらは
The prison association has created an understanding
刑務所協会は理解を深めました
That is to say, China is not only seriously
つまり、中国は本気でやっているだけではなく、
And maybe it's the worst country in the world
そしておそらくそれは世界で最悪の国です
In fact, in my research, there are
実際、私の研究では、
I have looked at the stats they use
彼らが使用している統計を見てみました
At that time, China had nothing to do with
当時は中国とは何の関係もなかった
There are few relevant statistics
関連する統計はほとんどありません
In many other cases, the use of
他の多くの場合、
For example, what is the one in Shanghai?
例えば上海のものは何でしょうか？
Concession in Shanghai
上海の租界
or some other zero-tax data pieced together
またはその他の税金ゼロのデータをつなぎ合わせたもの
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
It doesn't necessarily have solid statistics behind it.
必ずしも確実な統計が裏付けられているわけではありません。
But they created such an image
しかし、彼らはそのようなイメージを作り出しました
Maybe it's because I hope the government and compatriots will pay attention to it.
政府や同胞に注目してほしいからかもしれない。
created a
を作成しました
China has a very serious problem of combined disease
中国は複合疾患という非常に深刻な問題を抱えている
such a conclusion
そのような結論
but if you say that
でもそれを言うなら
then you clearly know
それならあなたは明らかに知っています
The Western consensus at the time was that
当時の西側のコンセンサスは次のとおりでした。
True Syndrome is very serious
真の症候群は非常に深刻です
It must be related to industrialization and urbanization
それは工業化と都市化に関連しているに違いありません
you become to explain
あなたは説明するようになる
There is one that Mr. Zeng just mentioned
曽氏が先ほど言及したものがあります。
I call it the Chinese Syndrome Mystery
私はこれをチャイニーズシンドロームミステリーと呼んでいます
that is
あれは
Such a disease is understandable in Europe, America and Japan
このような病気はヨーロッパ、アメリカ、日本では理解できます。
Why in an agricultural society like China
中国のような農業社会でなぜ？
will cause so many
非常に多くのことを引き起こすでしょう
they deeply hurt
彼らは深く傷つけた
It's like I can't understand
まるで理解できないみたいだ
right
右
then
それから
they use these
彼らはこれらを使用します
in the relevant researchers
関係する研究者の中で
To explain this phenomenon
この現象を説明するには
proposed some very
非常にいくつかの提案をしました
A very special explanation is that
非常に特殊な説明は、
whatever the cause of the disease
病気の原因が何であれ
The population distribution of patients, etc.
患者の人口分布等
Combined diseases in China are very different from those in the West
中国の複合疾患は西洋のそれとは大きく異なる
And it has a unique Chinese characteristic
そしてそれは中国独特の特徴を持っています
how to say
どのように言って
we now give an example
ここで例を挙げます
study at the University of Chicago
シカゴ大学で学ぶ
Dr. Lai Daoyuan, who taught at Shanghai Medical College, said
上海医科大学で教鞭を執った頼道源博士はこう語った。
Some people say that the amount of combined disease
病気の量を組み合わせると言う人もいます。
It is entirely related to the economic level of the people.
それは完全に人々の経済レベルに関係しています。
as i just said
今言ったように
It's a socioeconomic disease
それは社会経済的な病気です
So it's not at all
だから全然そんなことないよ
All kinds of preventive work are irrelevant
あらゆる種類の予防作業は無意味です
He said it was a close observation
彼はそれは綿密な観察だったと言いました
Although many people say
多くの人が言いますが、
but i don't think it's a foregone conclusion
しかし、それが当然の結論ではないと思います
He said because
彼はこう言いました。
What about us
私たちについてはどうでしょうか
rich people in our country
私たちの国の裕福な人々
Unlike American capitalists
アメリカの資本家とは違う
like to get together
集まるのが好き
everyone is very
みんなとても
live close together, a lot of people get together
近くに住んでいて、たくさんの人が集まる
I don't talk, and I don't like doing outdoor activities
私は話さないし、野外活動も好きではありません
And if you don't have the wind, the next generation is regarded as the standard of beauty
風がなければ次世代が美しさの基準になる
So that the chance of getting combined disease
そのため、複合疾患にかかる可能性が高くなります。
call poor people more
貧しい人々にもっと電話をかけなさい
The Great Disparity Between China and Foreign Countries
中国と外国の格差
say what they think
彼らが思っていることを言う
Chinese people with sickness and morality are totally different from Westerners
病気も道徳も西洋人とは全く違う中国人
Because people who get a lot are rich
たくさん得する人はお金持ちだから
Because they have some really bad habits
彼らは本当に悪い習慣を持っているので、
and cause them to get combined disease
そして複合疾患を引き起こす
So he cites a statistic
そこで彼はある統計を引用した
Patients with combined disease in Guangzhou
広州の複合疾患患者
First-class patients accounted for 8.4%
第一級患者は8.4％を占めた
What about ordinary patients?
一般の患者さんはどうでしょうか？
That is, only 2% of civilians
つまり民間人のうちわずか2％
three times worse
差三倍
From this we can know that in China
これからわか​​ることは、中国では
why this happened
なぜこれが起こったのか
not economic factors
経済的要因ではない
no nutritional factors
栄養要素はありません
but other factors
しかし他の要因
what about further
さらにどうですか
They also cite many
彼らはまた、多くのことを引用しています
Statistical reports on relevant clinical
関連する臨床に関する統計レポート
like this GA number
この GA 番号のように
The result of his research is that
彼の研究の結果は、
This is called Turbulic Losses in China
これを中国では乱流損失と呼んでいます
It is the combination of the lungs in China
中国の肺の組み合わせです
His Beijing Indications Combination Diseases
彼の北京の適応症 合併症
10 years of this
これの10年
Professor Ji Huanghao pointed out that
季黄豪教授は次のように指摘した。
The real thing is that everyone in China has
本当のことは、中国の誰もが持っているということです
The cause of combination disease is not what we just talked about
合併症の原因は今話したことではありません
those socioeconomic and nutritional factors
それらの社会経済的および栄養的要因
but unhygienic habits
しかし不衛生な習慣
Chinese habits will inevitably lead to a sense of integration
中国語を話す習慣は必然的に一体感につながる
Take a wide walk in the family
家族で広く散歩しましょう
Small hotel at home or in the village
自宅または村の小さなホテル
Both sick and healthy people sleep on the same bed
病気の人も健康な人も同じベッドで寝る
It's just that they sleep too close
それは彼らがあまりにも近くに寝ているだけです
and then the second one
そして2番目のもの
Whether at home, office or on the street
自宅でも、オフィスでも、街中でも
habit of spitting
唾を吐く習慣
not only taken for granted
当然のことと思われるだけでなく
and very common
そして非常に一般的な
So this is the habit of talking about spitting
だから唾を吐くのが習慣なんだ
What about the third one?
3番目はどうでしょうか？
After picking up food from the shared game
共有ゲームから食べ物を拾った後
The chopsticks are delivered directly to everyone's mouth
お箸は皆様の口に直接届けられます
So this is talking about communal food
これは共同食についての話です
That is, if there is a large bowl in the middle
つまり、真ん中に大きなボウルがある場合、
Your chopsticks go in to catch the cold
風邪を引くために箸が入ります
you put it in your mouth
あなたはそれを口に入れます
So if you have tuberculosis
したがって、結核に罹患している場合は、
After next time you send your germs to the bowl
次回、細菌をボウルに送った後
Then eat it for someone else
じゃあ誰かのために食べてね
So he imagined it was because of your family
だから彼はそれがあなたの家族のせいだと想像した
There are so many unhygienic habits at home
家には不衛生な習慣がたくさんある
so lead to
だから〜につながる
say this disease
この病気を言う
special one popular
特別な人気のある
And another reason
そしてもう一つの理由
It's just that your family is very big
ただあなたの家族はとても大きいです
you are very many
あなたはとても多いです
And the way we get along is too intimate
そして私たちの付き合い方は親密すぎる
He said that in China not only parents
中国では親だけではない、と彼は言った。
even grandparents
祖父母さえも
Boshu Uncle and other male elder relatives
房州の叔父とその他の男性の年配の親戚
Gu Yi Shen
グ・イーシェン
Mother-in-law, aunt and other female elder relatives
義母、叔母、その他の女性の年上の親戚
Cousins, brothers, sisters, and other relatives of the same generation
同世代のいとこ、兄弟、姉妹、その他の親戚
And the servants have very close contact with children.
そして、使用人は子供たちと非常に密接に接しています。
So what this imagines is that
それで、これが想像するのは、
in a very large family
とても大家族の中で
many people in close proximity
多くの人が近くにいる
Spread of disease as a result of communication
コミュニケーションによる病気の蔓延
But in fact at that time very
でも実はその時はとても
Chinese people are not all big families
中国人は大家族ばかりではない
there are a lot of people
人がいっぱいいます
there are a lot of single people
独身の人がたくさんいる
So this is actually a
これは実際には
A problematic description of a Chinese family at that time
当時の中国人家族に関する問題のある記述
But it also constituted the epidemiologist at that time
しかし、それは当時の疫学者の構成要素でもありました
considered a major reason the disease was transmitted in China
中国でこの病気が伝染した主な理由と考えられている
Okay, so from that point of view we take it back
さて、その観点から、私たちはそれを取り戻します
As I just said, at the beginning of the 20th century
さっきも言ったように、20世紀初頭には
The mainstream thinks that Fei Jie is compared with Chen Yin
主流派はフェイ・ジエをチェン・インと比較すると考えている
becomes a great contrast
素晴らしいコントラストになる
That is to say, Westerners at that time
つまり当時の西洋人は
or the predecessor of the then United Nations
または当時の国連の前身
The Ministry of Health of the League of Nations has always emphasized that Fei Jiehe is a Social Disease
国際連盟保健省は、費潔和は社会病であると常に強調してきた
But in the context of China
しかし、中国という文脈で考えると、
It has turned into a Family Disease
家族の病気になってしまった
based on family
家族に基づいて
And a disease that spreads in the family
そして家族に広がる病気
It does not stem from industrialization and urbanization
それは工業化や都市化から生じたものではありません
And the representative patients are not poor
そして代表的な患者は貧しいわけではない
Instead, they are rich people in big families who live a traditional life
その代わりに、彼らは伝統的な生活を送る大家族の裕福な人々です。
So it's not a social disease
だから社会病じゃないよ
but a family disease
でも家族の病気
And it's a disease unique to a Chinese family
そしてそれは中国人家族特有の病気です
This is equivalent to one of the
これは、次のいずれかに相当します。
an important consensus
重要な合意
That
それか
I'm thinking when you're listening now
あなたが今聞いているときに私は考えています
Do you think it's a bit
ちょっとだと思いますか
far-fetched or unimaginable
とんでもない、または想像を絶する
people at that time would come like this
当時の人はこうやって来るんだろうな
Conceive your place
自分の居場所を考えてみる
The reason next door is different from the whole world
隣が世界と違う理由
But it was indeed a
しかし、それは確かに
public health experts
公衆衛生の専門家
Even very credible public health experts
非常に信頼できる公衆衛生専門家であっても
an idea promoted
アイデアが推進されました
For example, here is a
たとえば、次のようなものがあります。
Female public health pioneers who once studied at Yale
かつてイェール大学で学んだ女性の公衆衛生先駆者
Ge Chenghui
葛成輝
She's sick in her Chinese with combination
彼女は中国語が組み合わさって病気だ
just talk about the Chinese
中国人についてだけ話してください
The relationship between Chinese people and combined disease
中国人と複合疾患との関係
point out that the Chinese people have the above bad habits
中国人には上記のような悪い習慣があると指摘する
So what?
だから何？
so that only one family member
家族が一人だけになるように
contracted disease
罹患した病気
before long
やがて
Half the family is a victim
家族の半分が被害者
Therefore, in the past, combined disease was called a master.
したがって、昔は複合病をマスターと呼んでいました。
I give this example to say
この例を挙げて言いたいのは、
what do you see her image like
彼女のイメージはどのように見えますか
this is not a society
ここは社会ではない
but to say
しかし言うこと
It was spread at home, right?
家に蔓延してたんですよね？
someone got it
誰かがそれを手に入れた
soon everyone will have
もうすぐ誰もが持つでしょう
And what about this matter
で、この件はどうなるの
The Chinese knew it before
中国人はそれを以前から知っていた
Because there is another person named Xijia in Chuanshilao.
川白老にはもう一人西佳という人がいるからです。
Xijia disease
喜嘉病
So he especially emphasized the word
そこで彼はこの言葉を特に強調した
It's the prison
それは刑務所です
it's actually interesting
それは本当に興味深いです
Because at that time in fact
というのも、実はその時は
That western doctor advocates the abolition of traditional Chinese medicine.
その西洋人医師は伝統的な中国医学の廃止を主張しています。
They hate using
彼らは使用することを嫌います
traditional Chinese medicine vocabulary
伝統的な中国医学の語彙
Then why do you specifically use a
では、なぜ具体的に
this looks like a weird
これは奇妙に見えます
very strange word
とても奇妙な言葉
It's especially interesting
特に興味深いです
a little bit reveals
少し明らかになります
Katsuragi would very much like to take advantage of an original
葛城さんはオリジナルをぜひ活用したいと考えています。
old vocabulary
古い語彙
to inspire everyone to a
みんなにインスピレーションを与えるために
inside the whole family
家族全員の中で
the disease spread
病気が蔓延した
And an image that causes people to die
そして人を死に至らしめるイメージ
The prison is
刑務所は
Passing on the master prison is a kind of prison disease
教師の刑務所への継承は一種の刑務所病です
This concept probably appeared around the seventh century
この概念はおそらく7世紀頃に登場したと考えられています
That basically reflects that
それは基本的にそれを反映しています
The Chinese at that time already knew
当時の中国人はすでに知っていた
this
これ
Tuberculosis is contagious
結核は伝染性です
But what about their theory?
しかし、彼らの理論はどうなのでしょうか？
Let's pass on the prison
私たちは刑務所に行きます
That is, after one person dies
つまり、人が死んだ後、
And then the worm after he died
そして、彼が死んだ後のワーム
leave his body
彼の体を離れる
and ran to his family
そして家族の元へ走った
So later lead to the family
それで後で家族につながります
Others contracted the disease and died
他にもこの病気に感染して死亡した人もいる
So everyone sounds like this, don't you think?
だからみんなこんな感じですよね？
It seems to be a bit like combined bacteria, right?
なんだか複合細菌みたいな感じですかね？
There is also an entity
実体もあるよ
just called a prison bug
ちょうど刑務所のバグと呼ばれた
and spread in the family
そして家族に広まる
so you take the word out
だからあなたは言葉を取り除きます
It seems to make others feel that
他人にもそう思わせてしまうようです
In fact, this disease in China is a family disease.
実際、中国ではこの病気は家族の病気です。
The Chinese Prison already knew
中国の刑務所はすでに知っていた
Words like this were even coined before
このような言葉は以前にも作られました
to describe this thing
このことを説明するには
And use this word to make everyone reinforce that
そしてこの言葉を使ってみんなにそのことを強調してもらいましょう
An image that feels like the disease is spreading in the family
家族内に病気が蔓延しているようなイメージ
But what?
でも何？
if we think about it
考えてみれば
Prison worms and combined infectious bacteria
刑務所の虫と複合感染性細菌
Behavioral patterns between
間の行動パターン
It's actually very different
実際には大きく異なります
how to say
どのように言って
I didn't just tell you that
ただそれを言っただけじゃない
The worm in the handed down prison is born after death
語り継がれる牢獄の虫は死後に生まれる
just run away, right?
ただ逃げるだけですよね？
But we save fuel and get infected with bacteria when we are actually alive
しかし、私たちは実際に生きていると燃料を節約し、細菌に感染します。
passed on while alive
生きながらに受け継がれてきた
So according to Academician Liang Qizi and
学者の梁啓子氏によれば、
Research by Mr. Li Jianmin of Shi Yisuo
Shi YsuoのLi Jianmin氏による研究
The reason why the concept of the so-called master is the most popular
いわゆるマスターという概念が最も人気がある理由
In fact, it is a Buddhist or Taoist concept.
実際、それは仏教または道教の概念です。
It means that in a family
つまり、家族の中で
your father's eg your karma
あなたの父親の、例えばあなたのカルマ
Your karma will be transmitted equal to
あなたのカルマは同等に伝達されます
Gekqua passed down to others in the family
家族に受け継がれた月華
It's actually kind of like an inheritance
それは実際にある種の遺産のようなものです
Do you understand what I mean?
私の言っている意味が分かりますか？
That is to say, you have a lot of karma
つまり、あなたにはたくさんのカルマがあるということです
Maybe the merit you do and your karma
もしかしたらあなたが行った功徳とあなたのカルマ
on your dad
あなたのお父さんについて
Your dad's passing only this all goes to
あなたのお父さんが亡くなりました、これだけがすべてです
on your next generation
あなたの次世代について
Nao Chongzhi is just a part of it
ナオ・チョンジはその一部に過ぎません
In other words, the transmission process
つまり、送信プロセスは、
In fact, it is related to the concept of religion.
実は、それは宗教の概念と関係しています。
not because you live together
一緒に住んでいるからではない
but now
でも今
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Katsuragi Hui he re-established the family and disease
葛城慧は家族と病気を再構築しました
a relation through the word
言葉を通しての関係
He mentioned the life-saving
彼は人命救助について言及した
to highlight family members
家族を強調するために
The horrible situation of widespread labor sickness
労働病が蔓延する悲惨な状況
But the concept of home
しかし、家の概念は、
There has been a conversion
変換がありました
He highlights that it is indeed family
彼はそれがまさに家族であることを強調した
is a new one family concept
新しいワンファミリーコンセプトです
relationship with disease
病気との関係
It's not about the religious
宗教の話じゃないよ
A transmission of merit and karma
功徳とカルマの伝達
It's about family members being together
それは家族が一緒にいるということです
Intimate interaction day and night
昼も夜も親密な交流
causing a disease to spread
病気の蔓延を引き起こす
So it's kind of like saving old and new from Pingzhuang
つまり、平荘から古いものと新しいものを保存するようなものです
right
右
On the one hand, it makes you feel a sense of fear
一方で、恐怖感も感じさせます
On the other hand, I changed it to something
一方で、何かに置き換えられてしまった
So what? The family has grown from a religious-ethical organization
それで何が? 家族は宗教倫理団体から成長した
become a physical cohabitation
物理的な同棲になる
But from these places you will see
しかし、これらの場所から見ると、
That is to say, he advocated this life-saving
つまり、彼はこの救命を提唱したのです。
is key for highlighting, festival and dissemination
ハイライト、フェスティバル、普及の鍵となる
family in china
中国の家族
So and in fact in
それで、そして実際に
After the concept became popular
このコンセプトが広まってからは
let's see that
それを見てみましょう
Just like now sometimes our teachers
今みたいに時々私たちの先生たちも
Don't know what students write their experience?
学生が自分の経験について何を書いているか知りませんか?
Nafang Primary School invites many students
納芳小学校は多くの生徒を招待します
to write articles
記事を書く
many students started
多くの生徒が始めました
with a look of fear
恐怖の表情で
looking at his parents and grandparents
彼の両親や祖父母を見ながら
and say i can feel
そして私は感じることができると言う
the way my grandfather ate or spit
祖父の食べ方や吐き方
and then how to pass it on to my grandmother
そしてそれを祖母にどうやって伝えるか
And later killed my brothers and sisters
そしてその後、私の兄弟や姉妹を殺しました
I just feel an unprecedented
まさに前例のないことを感じています
you by these
あなたはこれらによって
are you at home
家にいますか
This is your dearest person
これはあなたの最愛の人です
but you feel
でもあなたは感じます
They passed the disease on to you
彼らはあなたに病気を移しました
Then you can't protect yourself from a sense of fear
そうなると恐怖感から身を守ることができなくなります
That was a very common feeling at that time
当時はそれがごく普通の感覚だった
good
良い
So from this point of view you see
この観点から見ると、
it's really a very different
それは本当に全く違うものです
understanding of a disease
病気の理解
in China in the 1930s
1930年代の中国で
People Don't Think Syndrome Is Industrialization
人々は症候群が工業化だとは考えていない
caused by urbanization
都市化によって引き起こされる
If so, it is a process of modernization
もしそうなら、それは近代化のプロセスです
In fact in combination disease is understood as
実際、複合疾患では次のように理解されます。
We feel it when Social disease
社会病のときに私たちはそれを感じます
would be considered a disease of civilization
文明病とみなされるだろう
disease caused by civilization
文明が引き起こした病気
But at that time the Chinese believed that
しかし、当時の中国人は次のように信じていました。
Nor do they see the state as actively involved in
また、国家が積極的に関与しているとも考えていない。
can solve this problem
この問題を解決できる
So you won't learn Japanese like
だから、あなたは日本語を学ぶことはできません
I think the government needs to intervene
政府が介入する必要があると思う
In fact, the government cannot
実際、政府はそれができない
to solve this problem
この問題を解決するために
what about the opposite
逆はどうですか
in Chinese understanding
中国語の理解で
this disease
この病気
including even public health officials
公衆衛生当局者も含めて
and all things think
そしてすべてのものは考える
The Culprit of Syndrome in China
中国症候群の犯人
in a traditional Chinese family
伝統的な中国の家庭で
long-term unhygienic
長期的には不衛生
a personal habit
個人的な習慣
So this is how to understand the disease
これが病気を理解する方法です
becomes quite the opposite
まったく逆になります
understood from the west
西からわかる
This is caused by modernization
これは近代化が原因です
understood in Chinese
中国語で理解できる
Because you are too present in a traditional family
あなたは伝統的な家族の中に存在しすぎているからです
you have this disease
あなたはこの病気にかかっています
So although you are not industrialized
つまり、工業化されていないにもかかわらず、
but you get very sick with this
しかし、これではとても気分が悪くなる
That even some public health experts pointed out
一部の公衆衛生専門家も指摘している
The ultimate solution to the combined disease in China
中国の複合病に対する究極の解決策
Know that it is a small family that fully adopts Europe and the United States
ヨーロッパとアメリカを完全に取り入れた小さな家族であることを知ってください
Then this may be better than the dining table we just talked about
それなら、さっき話したダイニングテーブルよりこっちのほうがいいかもね
more amazing
もっとすごい
That is to say, in order to solve a disease
つまり、病気を解決するためには、
you have to change
あなたは変わらなければなりません
You want everyone's family system to change
みんなの家族制度を変えてほしい
but you can feel it
でもあなたはそれを感じることができます
At that time, public health experts thought
当時の公衆衛生の専門家はどのようなことを考えていたか
with their understanding of the disease
病気に対する彼らの理解とともに
How many reasons for its establishment are related to
設立の理由はいくつありますか?
related to the family environment
家庭環境に関わるもの
If we speak in more abstract language
もっと抽象的な言葉で話すと
we can say
と言えます
This is called the pathologicalization of the traditional Chinese family
これは中国の伝統的な家族の病理学化と呼ばれます
as you think
あなたが考えるように
You imagine this home as the cause of all kinds of diseases
あなたはこの家があらゆる種類の病気の原因であると想像します
Then there's the harm it brings to everyone
そして、それがすべての人にもたらす害があります
So it should have been a
したがって、それは
All of your values, right?
あなたの価値のすべてですよね？
you get warm
あなたは暖かくなります
place of warmth and hugs
温もりと抱擁の場所
You now feel like it's the source of all your problems
あなたは今、それがすべての問題の原因であるように感じています
is a like a cause
原因のようなものです
Pathologicalization of a Traditional Family
伝統的家族の病理学化
That's the point at that time
それがその時のポイントです
A conclusion drawn on disease
病気に関して導き出された結論
I'm talking here, do you have any questions?
ここで話していますが、何か質問はありますか？
Ruiyou can first propose
Ruiyouは最初にプロポーズすることができます
please
お願いします
This has something to do with the noble family, is it in the noble family?
これは貴族と関係があるのですが、貴族ですか？
Um
えーっと
that red chinchilla
あの赤いチンチラ
yes
はい
right
右
For this noble family, it is a stump
この貴族にとって、それは切り株です
The topic of remnants
残骸の話題
right
右
Like I mentioned the adjacent generation domain just now?
先ほど隣接ドメインについて触れたように？
so you asked this question, right?
それでこの質問をしたんですよね？
What he meant was that
彼が言いたかったのは、
From a certain point of view, the environment of this disease
ある観点から見ると、この病気の環境は
In fact, there is something in that culture
実際、その文化には何かがあります
one that would have encouraged people
人々を勇気づけたであろうもの
caused by the lifestyles that people are encouraged to adopt
人々が採用するよう奨励されているライフスタイルによって引き起こされる
Then what you just said he didn't talk about the remnants
それから、あなたが今言ったことは、彼は残党については話していませんでした
just say you don't like doing outdoor activities
野外活動は好きではないとだけ言ってください
this is one of the important points
これは重要なポイントの 1 つです
For example, another point is to say
たとえば、もう一つのポイントは、
He'll keep emphasizing like I just didn't say
彼は私が言っていなかったように強調し続けるでしょう
western opinion says
西側の意見は言う
The problem to be solved in anatomical diseases is the problem of lighting
解剖学的疾患で解決すべき問題は照明の問題です
right
右
But relatively speaking
でも相対的に言えば
China has always been afraid of the wind
中国は常に風を恐れてきた
The doors and windows are tightly closed
ドアも窓もしっかりと閉められている
I don't want to go outside
外に出たくない
This is what was said more
これはさらに話題になりました
silkworm feet to no direct connection there
蚕の足とそこには直接の関係はない
Um
えーっと
in
の
because it is
その理由は
Hakka is you
ハッカはあなたです
they are you
彼らはあなたです
they are all dame of labor
彼らは皆労働者のお嬢様です
often done in agricultural products
農産物でよく行われる
right
右
yes
はい
then we
それから私たち
Speaking of Song and Ming Dynasties
宋・明といえば
right
右
Three Canons of Lecturers
講師の 3 つの規範
They are all Hakka dames
彼らは全員客家夫人です
yes
はい
are playing and teaching abroad
海外で演奏したり教えたりしている
When the Republic of China came out of the clouds
中華民国が雲から現れたとき
yes
はい
they go all the way
彼らはどこまでも行く
Lecture Committee
講演会委員会
dame outside a foreign country
外国の女性
yes
はい
I will later
後で行きます
He will appear in this story later
彼は後ほどこの物語に登場します
you wait a moment
ちょっと待ってください
right
右
Then I just stopped here to tell you
それから、私はあなたに伝えるためにここで立ち止まりました
The stories I just told you are all about a public health expert.
私が今お話しした話はすべて公衆衛生の専門家に関するものです。
right
右
And everyone can hear that it was actually the
そして、それが実際にあったことは誰もが聞くことができます。
Working in China
中国で働く
Medical elites at home and abroad
国内外の医療エリート
But they came to a very surprising conclusion
しかし彼らは非常に驚くべき結論に達しました
That is to say, this is a very serious problem.
つまり、これは非常に深刻な問題なのです。
But Chen Yin is completely different from the West
しかし、チェン・インは西洋とはまったく異なります
And this Chen Yin directly came from
そして、このチェンインは直接来ました
A condition of the family originating in China
中国に由来する家族の条件
That's why I said that in the West it is regarded as a
だからこそ私は、西洋ではそれが
social disease
社会病
Treated as a family disease in China
中国では家族病として扱われている
put it in the history of medicine
医学の歴史に載せてください
is a very surprising thing
とても驚くべきことです
Because logically speaking, they have also received this training.
論理的に言えば、彼らもこの訓練を受けているからです。
And everyone just saw the Lai Dou I cited
そして誰もが私が引用したライ・ドゥを見たところです
His first sentence is
彼の最初の文は、
In China, this problem should not only be an economic problem
中国では、この問題は単なる経済問題ではないはずだ
Indicates that he knows that the world believes that
世界がそう信じていることを彼が知っていることを示します
It's a socioeconomic issue, right?
それは社会経済的な問題ですよね？
But we are such a one that puts all the problems
でも私たちはすべての問題を抱えているような存在です
It all belongs to China, this belongs to the family
それはすべて中国のもの、これは家族のものです
Surprising words in medical treatment
医療現場での意外な言葉
But if we put him in
でも彼を入れたら
Modern Chinese History in the 20th Century
20世紀中国現代史
or modern history
あるいは現代史
I am the director of the modern history of the surrounding
私は周囲の近現代史のディレクターです
That is, if we break away from medical
つまり、医療から離れると、
put him in the mainstream of modern history
彼を現代史の主流に据える
In fact it's common sense
実はそれが常識なんです
that's the one
それだ
This is a book written by Susan Glasser
これはスーザン・グラッサーによって書かれた本です
It's called Transfusions of Family and State
それは「家族と国家の輸血」と呼ばれるものです
Let’s talk about how people in modern China regard this family
現代中国の人々がこの家族をどのように見ているかについて話しましょう
Some visions and ideas of the country
この国のビジョンやアイデア
It is written in this book that at that time
この本には当時のことが書かれていますが、
In fact, whether it is the Kuomintang or the Communist Party
実際、国民党であろうと共産党であろうと、
Or journalistic campaigners
あるいはジャーナリスト活動家
Everyone thinks the problem is with the family
問題は家族にあると誰もが思っている
Feeling that family is at the heart of the problem
家族が問題の中心にあると感じる
So what I just told you is that
それで、私が今あなたに話したのは、
From the perspective of medical history, we
私たちは病歴の観点から、
It's surprising how you came to this conclusion
どうやってこの結論に至ったのか不思議です
But if you're out of medical history
ただし、病歴がない場合は、
you go back to that big social environment
あなたはその大きな社会環境に戻ります
Everyone already felt the problem
誰もがすでに問題を感じていました
It's all about the family
それはすべて家族に関するものです
you know what i mean
私の言っていることが分かるよね
Then I will give you the most drastic example
それでは、最も大胆な例を示します
The most intense is Fu Sinian
最も強烈なのはフー・シニアンです
His first issue in Xinchao
新潮での彼の最初の号
You see, this is also the first issue
ほら、これも最初の問題です
publish an article
記事を公開する
called the root of all evil
諸悪の根源と呼ばれる
He said that China is the root of all evil
中国が諸悪の根源だと彼は言った
is a Chinese family
中国人の家族です
In fact, we rarely get this
実際、これが得られることはほとんどありません
At that time it was
当時はそうでした
very harsh criticism
非常に厳しい批判
Then why did he say
ではなぜ彼はこう言ったのか
The Chinese family is the root of all evil in China
中国の諸悪の根源は中国人家族だ
He said that because Chinese families are
彼は、中国人の家族は
The biggest force that destroys personality
人格を破壊する最大の力
what does that mean he said
彼が言ったのはどういう意味ですか
from the day the child was born
子供が生まれた日から
teach him how to be tough
彼にタフになる方法を教えてください
how to deny yourself
自分を否定する方法
how to be your father and mother's son
あなたの父親と母親の息子になるにはどうすればよいですか
never teach him to do
彼にやるべきことを決して教えない
his being himself
彼自身という存在
so it's a lot like your kid
だからあなたの子供によく似ています
not one of your children
あなたの子供ではありません
The version from a hundred years ago, right?
百年前のバージョンですよね？
He just said don't teach him to catch himself
彼はただ、自分自身を捕まえるように教えないでと言っただけです
In a word it is
一言で言えばそうです
extreme destruction of personality
極端な人格破壊
So he felt that the root of all evil
そこで彼は、諸悪の根源は何かと感じた。
It means that after you destroy a person's personality
つまり、人の人格を破壊した後、
All the above questions come from here
上記の質問はすべてここから来ています
because the person has lost autonomy
その人が自主性を失っているからです
with his individuality
彼の個性で
what about in this article
この記事ではどうですか
He thinks the key is family
彼は鍵は家族だと考えている
destroy personality
人格を破壊する
But what?
でも何？
In this article, his personalities are put in quotation marks more than a dozen times
この記事では、彼の性格が十数回引用符で囲まれています。
So he knows full well the word is new
だから彼はその言葉が新しいことをよく知っている
At that time, people didn't know what personality was
当時、人々は個性とは何かを知りませんでした
because why
なぜならなぜ
Because including individuals and individuals are actually new words just created
個人と個人を含めるのは実際には新しく作られたばかりの言葉だから
It's from Japanese, it's the translation
日本語からの翻訳です
individual and individualism have just been introduced
個人と個人主義は導入されたばかりです
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
That Fussian critique of the Chinese family
中国人家族に対するあのフーシアン批判
from a libertarian individualistic standpoint
リバタリアン個人主義の観点から
Absolutely in this original home setting
まさにこのオリジナルのホーム環境で
Don't let children decide what industry they want to go
子どもたちに行きたい業界を決めさせないでください
If you don't let him get married, you have to listen to the family's orders.
彼を結婚させないなら、家族の命令を聞かなければなりません。
so that he loses one of his autonomy as an individual
個人としての自主性を失うことになる
let him call it a personality
それを個性と呼ばせてください
So that's a source of his critique
それが彼の批評の源だ
That's called the root of all evil
それが諸悪の根源と呼ばれる
There are many criticisms in that book from this angle.
この本にはこの観点からの批判がたくさんあります。
Even Hu Shi, the dean of the month
今月の学部長である胡詩でさえも
He said that China used to feel the most unfilial
中国はかつて最も親不孝だと感じていたと彼は語った。
That means you are not filial to your grandfather, right?
それって、おじいちゃんに親孝行してないってことですよね？
unfilial offspring
親不孝な子孫
He said that even if you are not filial, you will make progress
親孝行できなくても進歩するよって言ってた
From the perspective of evolution, there is no way to progress without mutation
進化の観点から見ると、突然変異なしに進歩する方法はありません
So it's good for everyone to be unfilial
だから親不孝は誰でも良いことだ
it was one of those days
それはそんな日の一つでした
such a critical position
そのような重要な立場
So let's look at it from this point of view
それでは、この観点から見てみましょう
Actually we have a puzzle
実はパズルがあります
That's why two sports that look so different
だからこそ、この 2 つのスポーツは大きく異なって見えるのです
It seems like we have a date
デートがあるようです
It's the science-based Fei Jiehe's prevention and control campaign
それは科学に基づいたフィッツジェラルド予防キャンペーンです
I use the picture of Katsuragi Club as a representative
葛城クラブの写真を代表として使用させていただきます
make it easier for everyone to remember
誰もが覚えやすいようにする
and this individualistic
そしてこの個性的な
Seems like a home improvement movement based on an ideology
イデオロギーに基づいた住宅改善運動のように見える
They seem to have made an appointment, right?
彼らは約束をしたようですよね？
They all think the problem is the same regardless
彼らは皆、問題は同じだと考えている
Seeing the Chinese family as the root of the problem
中国人家族が問題の根源であると考える
serious personal harm
重大な人身被害
On Katsuragi's side, right?
葛城さん側ですよね？
It's the family that passed the disease on to this young man.
この若者に病気を移したのは家族です。
a student an individual
学生、個人
I just said that many young students feel
多くの若い学生が感じていると先ほど言いました
They saw their body's being grandpa
彼らは自分たちの体がおじいちゃんになっているのを見た
a threat from a grandfather or father
祖父または父親からの脅迫
what about here
ここはどうですか
In the year of Fuji, it is also said that they were all killed by their parents.
富士の年に両親に皆殺されたという。
destroy your personality
自分の人格を破壊する
Why is this one derived from the scientific
なぜこれが科学的根拠に基づいているのか
with a value derived from society
社会から得られる価値観で
It seems that two people are walking together
二人で歩いているようだ
right
右
as if supporting each other
お互いをサポートするかのように
Is this a coincidence
これは偶然ですか
if it is not a coincidence
それが偶然でないなら
What is the mechanism behind the difference?
その違いの背後にあるメカニズムは何ですか？
I'm talking about do you have any friends here?
私が話しているのは、ここに友達はいますか？
any ideas
何か案は
Because it looks really close, right?
だってすごく近くに見えるじゃないですか。
is that a coincidence
それは偶然ですか
you want to say please say
言いたいのなら言ってください
please i want to ask
お願いしたいのですが
And about the house behind it is
そしてその後ろの家については、
I mean after World War II
つまり第二次世界大戦後
or card interface
またはカードインターフェイス
That is, the Allied Forces keep pushing
つまり、連合軍は押し続けます
Whether it is Japan or
日本であっても、
Dongdong has already
東東はすでに
Because of BCG to treat
BCG治療のため
In the case of National Taiwan University Hospital
国立台湾大学病院の場合
he will go to therapy
彼はセラピーに行くつもりです
They had a lot of medical students at the time
当時は医学生がたくさんいました
Including treatment with convalescence
回復期治療を含む
BCG
BCG
and treatment with Feijie and toxin
フェイジエと毒素による治​​療
But they all belong to the family structure of Confucian society
しかし、彼らは皆、儒教社会の家族構成に属しています。
As a result we can learn one thing
その結果、私たちは一つのことを学ぶことができます
That is to say, local Chinese
つまり、地元の中国人
Although they bring the problem home
彼らは問題を家に持ち帰りますが、
But Fei Jie and the problem is still serious
しかし、フェイ・ジエと問題は依然として深刻である
Based on the medical data in Taiwan at that time
当時の台湾の医療データをもとに
Hygienic habits in Taiwan at that time
当時の台湾の衛生習慣
running water etc
流水など
Popular in several provinces of leading China
中国主要地域のいくつかの省で人気
even at the level of an itch
かゆみのレベルでも
But he Feige and the problem is still serious
しかし、ファイギと問題は依然として深刻だ
so i personally think
だから私は個人的に思う
you take your problems home
あなたは問題を家に持ち帰ります
Or use it as Confucianism
あるいは儒教として使う
or problematic points in feudal thought
あるいは封建思想の問題点
I think a little bit at the time
その時に少し思うのですが
Hua Po fallacy
華坡の誤謬
What
何
a Huapo fallacy
フアポの誤謬
that is to say a
つまり
how to explain
どのように説明するか
is a fallacy
それは誤謬です
everyone is one of a kind
誰もが一つです
everyone thinks
誰もが思う
It's the whole problem. All problems boil down to this
それがすべての問題です すべての問題は要約するとこれです
Even if everyone has no money today
たとえ今日誰もがお金を持っていなくても
Or everyone has no culture
あるいは誰もが文化を持っていない
It's all because of family
全部家族のせいだよ
So I think it's a time
だから、そういう時期だと思うよ
No matter what the New Culture Movement says
新文化運動が何と言おうと
At that time, everyone had a trend
あの頃は誰もがトレンドを持っていた
so is it a coincidence
それは偶然ですか
I think it was some intellectuals at that time
当時は一部の知識人だったと思います
Some people like Cai Peihuo sum it up as
蔡培虎のような人は、次のように要約しています。
Inductive result
帰納的結果
But as for the cost, it was finally because of BCG
でもコスト的にはBCGのせいで最終的には
fully treated
完全に治療された
so i feel like saying
だから言いたい気がする
If it can be classified as a family problem
家族の問題として分類できる場合
I think it's still a little biased
まだ少し偏見があると思います
But I don't know what professor you think
でも教授がどう思ってるかは分からない
about this one thing
この一つのことについて
Yes, first you gave a very important background
はい、最初に非常に重要な背景を説明しました
That’s what we just said, only the germ theory, right?
それは私たちが今言ったことです、細菌理論だけですよね？
But there is no cure
しかし、治療法はありません
As far as the time I am talking about is
私が話している時間に関して言えば、
there is no cure at all
治療法はまったくありません
just like you said
あなたが言ったように
So back then it was actually just a nursing home
つまり、当時は実際には単なる老人ホームでした
that is no effective therapy
それは効果的な治療法ではありません
So this question is another very important background
この質問はもう一つの非常に重要な背景です
in this story
この物語の中で
Then another big difference
それからもう一つの大きな違いは
actually
実際
I just had no chance to speak
ただ話す機会がなかった
That is to say, in the context of Japan just now
つまり、今の日本の文脈で言えば、
Have treated it as a Social Disease
それを社会病として扱ってきた
right
右
like i said
私が言ったように
So that later the Japanese royal family began
その後、日本の皇室が始まった
is to provide a large fund
多額の資金を提供することです
To solve the problem of Japanese workers
日本人労働者の問題を解決するために
This puzzling and problematic thing for workers
労働者にとってこの不可解で問題のあること
would feel like saying
と言いたくなるだろう
you improve its nutrition
あなたはその栄養を改善します
improve its living environment
生活環境を改善する
might help it
それは役立つかもしれない
You treat it like a Social Disease
あなたはそれを社会病のように扱っています
to deal with
対処する
Well, today this is in the context of China
さて、今日は中国の文脈での話です
I just because of that time
あの時だからこそ
What I didn't say carefully is
慎重に言わなかったのは、
Actually at that time
実はあの時
The one who was taken by Xiehe Hospital
謝和病院に運ばれた人
a very important leader
とても重要なリーダー
His name is John Grant
彼の名前はジョン・グラントです
is listed as one of the John Hopkins
ジョン・ホプキンスの一人としてリストされている
public health hero
公衛英雄
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
Let's not prioritize combination disease
合併症を優先しないようにしましょう
Because if he's Social Disease
なぜなら彼が社会病なら
It just requires the government to invest a lot of money
政府が巨額の資金を投入する必要があるだけだ
to improve the financial environment
金融環境を改善するために
if that doesn't work
それがうまくいかない場合
So in fact our story
実際、私たちの物語
how much is in that environment
その環境ではどれくらいですか
you think you can't help
あなたは助けられないと思っていますか
if you think about it
考えてみれば
into a social disease
社会病に陥る
everyone helpless
みんな無力
Then if you emphasize it as a
次に、それを次のように強調すると、
unhygienic habits
不衛生な習慣
words that cause disease
病気の原因となる言葉
at least we can do something
少なくとも私たちには何かができる
So it's kind of in this vein
ということで、こういう流れですね
what happened
どうしたの
So you said that is not to say
だから、それは違うとあなたは言いました
slightly incorrect
少し間違っています
This story is now undeniably incorrect
この話は今や間違いなく間違っています
So from what we say today
今日私たちが話すことから
Fei Jie and Qi is a respiratory disease
フェイ・ジエとチーは呼吸器疾患です
right
右
not at all through this
これではまったく
That is to say, the situation of droplet infection
つまり飛沫感染の状況
So the concept is
したがって、コンセプトは
From today's point of view
今日の観点から見ると
scientifically incorrect
科学的に間違っている
but people at that time
でも当時の人たちは
It is the leading scientist we are talking about
それは私たちが話している一流の科学者です
Like the Wuliande I just mentioned
さっき言った五連徳みたいに
he always believed it
彼はいつもそう信じていた
so he
彼は
He's even a nominee over there
彼はあそこの候補者でもある
he will think
彼は考えるだろう
this
これ
We're going to treat it like a disease like this
このような病気のように扱うつもりです
So from the people at that time
それで当時の人たちからは
they will think
彼らは考えるだろう
Actually this is the question I just asked
実はこれは私が今した質問なのです
At that time, people may think that
その時、人々はこう思うかもしれません。
Scientists at the time
当時の科学者
they may feel
彼らは感じるかもしれない
It's the best they can have
それが彼らが持てる最高のものだ
and has the most evidence
そして最も多くの証拠を持っています
The display should face this direction
ディスプレイはこの方向を向く必要があります
But the problem is that this is at the same time
しかし問題は、これは同時に
In fact, it is also related to a large social and cultural environment
実際、それは大きな社会的および文化的環境にも関係しています
closely related
密接に関係している
Are they under his influence?
彼らは彼の影響下にあるのでしょうか？
it's a question I posed
それは私が出した質問です
I think what you just said was that
それから、あなたが今言ったことは次のようなことだと思います
maybe there is no way to say
もしかしたら言う方法はないかもしれない
that's how you feel, don't you
そう感じますよね
Do you have any other friends or want to say something here?
他に友達がいますか、それともここで何か言いたいことがありますか？
there is a gentleman over here please
ここに紳士がいますのでお願いします
right
右
my personal opinion
私の個人的な意見
when China was in the present
中国が現在にあった頃
Sanitary conditions will be inconvenient
衛生状態が不便になる
yes also bad
はい、それも悪いです
Yes, for example, a child poops on the bed
はい、たとえば、子供がベッドの上でうんちをしたとします。
how to clean
掃除の仕方
elder
長老
This dying old man or something
この瀕死の老人か何か
sick old man
病気の老人
What to do with the back row
後列はどうするか
I thought it was time to go far
遠くへ行く時が来たと思った
Right, the doorman outside Sijakun
そう、シジャクンの外のドアマンです
yes there is such a situation
はい、そのような状況があります
Is it a matter of Ovarian?
それは変化の問題ですか？
Infected and mixed
感染と混合
For example, we are in Minbei
たとえば、私たちは民北にいます
there is a play called what
なんていうドラマがあります
Such a large communal situation
このような大きな共同体状況
So to make this contagion update the expansion
この伝染性のアップデートを拡大するには
Yes, as for not controlling me
そう、私をコントロールしないことに関しては
yes thank you
はい、ありがとうございます
just him
彼だけ
That's exactly what people at the time imagined.
それはまさに当時の人々が想像していたものです。
I think it's a
だと思います
many people live together
多くの人が一緒に住んでいます
And we live together very closely
そして私たちはとても近くで一緒に暮らしています
mix everything together
すべてを混ぜ合わせる
caused by
のせいで
At that time, such a situation was also described
そんな様子も描かれていました
ok then i am speaking
わかりました、それでは話します
just if it's not a coincidence
それが偶然でなければ
What might be the mechanism behind the difference
この違いの背後にあるメカニズムは何でしょうか
I will give you a report
ご報告させていただきます
In fact, a possible mechanism behind it is that
実際、その背後にある考えられるメカニズムは次のとおりです。
in the west
西に
Three important health systems
3 つの重要な医療システム
In fact, it simultaneously creates three
実際には、同時に 3 つが作成されます。
a different identity
異なるアイデンティティ
How should I put it? Let me talk about the first example.
なんというか、最初の例についてお話します。
The first example is quarantine
最初の例は隔離です
Everyone knows today, right?
今日はみんな知ってるよね？
It reinforces a sovereign state
それは主権国家を強化する
Identity within a sovereign state
主権国家におけるアイデンティティ
because the threat we feel at this time
なぜなら、現時点で私たちが感じている脅威は
It's all from the outside, right?
それはすべて外側からですよね？
from the port from outside
港から 外から
So you in order to prevent this disease
したがって、この病気を予防するには
Just like the FAKE we talked about before
さっき話したFAKEみたいに
In fact, Quarantine is related to the Black Death, right?
実際、検疫は黒死病と関連していますよね?
So you will put Jiang Jie in your country
それで蒋介石を自分の国に置くのですか
Fortify it, don't let outsiders in
要塞を強化し、部外者を入れないでください
that in doing so
そうすることで
In fact, you have to have the sovereignty of a sovereign country
実際には、主権国家の主権を持たなければなりません
you control the port
あなたがポートを制御します
But doing it will also let the people inside
しかし同時に、それは内部にいる人々を
stronger feeling says
より強い感情が言う
The threat is from outside
脅威は外部から来る
In fact, many times in the 19th century
実際、19世紀には何度も
Everyone names the disease
みんなが病気の名前を付ける
are named after another country.
他の国の名前が付けられています。
That is to say, the American drug is from another country.
つまり、アメリカの薬は別の国から来たものです。
right
右
So this health system of this quarantine
つまり、この医療検疫システムは
Its boundaries are equivalent to surrounding a
その境界は、周囲を囲むことと同等です。
space on the map
地図上のスペース
and make you inside
そしてあなたを中に入れてください
it requires you to be a sovereign state
主権国家であることが必要です
To be able to implement such a health system
このような医療システムを実現できるようになるには
while executing
実行中
In the process of implementation, it will be further strengthened
実装の過程でさらに強化されます
The people inside feel that we are a community of life
内部の人々は私たちが生命の共同体であると感じています
Then we have common interests
それから私たちには共通の興味があります
Then isolate yourself from outside threats.
次に、外部の脅威から自分を隔離します。
That's why something like
だからこそ、次のようなもの
Since the outbreak of COVID-19, many people will say
新型コロナウイルス感染症の流行以来、多くの人がこう言うだろう。
Don't we claim to be entering a globalized world?
私たちはグローバル化された世界に突入していると主張していませんか?
Why all of a sudden
なぜ突然
The gates are closed
門は閉まっています
right
右
In fact, at the beginning, no one wanted to close the door.
実際、最初は誰もドアを閉めようとはしませんでした。
Because in fact, this method was rarely used by the nineteenth century.
実際、この方法は 19 世紀までにほとんど使用されていなかったからです。
because the adoption will lead to
養子縁組は次のことにつながるからです
disruption of international trade
国際貿易の混乱
interruption of communication
通信の中断
But when the disease comes, you will be forced to take this approach
しかし、病気が発生すると、このアプローチを取らざるを得なくなります。
So in fact, COVID-19 is forcing us to adopt a
実際、新型コロナウイルス感染症により、私たちは
It hasn't been done for a long time
長い間行われていなかった
but at the same time it will
しかし同時にそれは
Let you feel a strong anti-globalization force
強烈な反グローバリゼーションの力を感じさせる
consolidated a sovereign state
主権国家を強化した
self-identity
自己アイデンティティ
I think that's what we've all experienced
それは誰もが経験したことだと思います
a very large force
非常に強い力
And the second one is health science in the nineteenth century
2つ目は19世紀の健康科学です
A boundary it reinforces is an anatomical body
それが強化する境界は解剖学的身体です
how to say everyone has heard
誰もが聞いたことがあると言う方法
Chinese public health
中国の公衆衛生
It's John Snow, right?
ジョン・スノウですよね？
He found a water
彼は水を見つけた
a water supply place
給水所
spreads mischief
いたずらを広める
So only World Health Sciences
したがって、世界保健科学だけが
One of his concerns
彼の懸念の一つは
is my body
私の体です
relationship to my environment
私の環境との関係
anything can get in my body
私の体に何かが入る可能性があります
It's probably a cure, right?
それはおそらく治療法ですよね？
such as water
水などの
Or the air I breathe, etc.
あるいは私が吸う空気など。
that is
あれは
you will be very concerned about me this
あなたは私のことをとても心配してくれるでしょう
so-called anatomy students
いわゆる解剖学学生
it's my body
それは私の体です
around my whole skin
私の肌全体の周りに
I will pay attention to all the holes
すべての穴に注目します
Because that's where the disease comes in
そこから病気が始まるから
Then other diseases also come out from the hole
そうすると穴から他の病気も出てくる
So for example our pee and poop
たとえば、私たちのおしっこやうんち
suddenly became a big problem
突然大きな問題になった
It is Semitic Science
それはセム科学です
Just to build a sewer
下水道を作るためだけに
Because those things may make the disease
それらが病気の原因となる可能性があるため、
bring to others
他の人に持っていく
So there is even a
それで、
our pores
私たちの毛穴
and suddenly we have for our
そして突然、私たちのために
The sweat becomes a great concern, too
汗もすごく気になりますね
So the result of the development of this science
つまり、この科学の発展の結果は、
makes us pay unprecedented attention to
私たちにこれまでにない注意を払わせる
Our relationship with the environment
私たちと環境との関係
And pay attention to monitor
そしてモニターにも注目
The mouth of our body
私たちの体の口
And that is to say
つまり、
genitals, wait
性器、待ってください
There are pores and so on
毛穴などがある
So strengthened an anatomical body
解剖学的身体を強化した
the other one is
もう一つは
When does the boundary between our body and the environment
私たちの身体と環境の境界はいつ決まるのか
It's dangerous if you don't know
知らないと危ないよ
because you have to protect the border
国境を守らなければならないから
what is one of those dangerous times
危険な時期とは何ですか
that's when I'm going back to the environment
そのとき私は環境に戻ります
when i die
私が死ぬとき
So at that time, we will pay great attention to disposing of the dead body.
ですので、その際にはご遺体の処理には細心の注意を払います。
right
右
dead bodies suddenly become a big problem
死体が突然大きな問題になる
Then start the one around
それから周りのものを始めてください
The cemetery that was originally built in the city center
もともと市内中心部に建てられた墓地
All will be transferred to foreign affairs
全員外務省に異動する
It's like saying our excrement is suddenly down the drain
私たちの排泄物が突然排水溝に落ちたと言っているようなものです
So the rise of this science
この科学の台頭により、
will strengthen our one is to say
私たちのことを強化してくれるでしょう、それは言うことです
you feel this in your body
あなたはこれを体で感じます
Note that a skin surrounds all the holes
すべての穴がスキンで囲まれていることに注意してください
Then this is the health science of Xiyou Century
これがXiyou Centuryの健康科学です
Then to personal hygiene in the first half of the second century
その後、2世紀前半の個人衛生へ
His focus is not on our relationship to our environment
彼の焦点は私たちの環境との関係ではありません
but the exchange of substances between the bodies
しかし、身体間の物質の交換は
like we just saw this picture right?
この写真を見たばかりですよね？
Is the focus today on my relationship with the environment?
今日の焦点は私と環境の関係ですか?
Rather, from certain fluids in another person's body
むしろ、他人の体内の特定の体液から
run to my problem
私の問題に向かって走ってください
Kissing, for example, suddenly became a very dangerous act.
たとえば、キスは突然非常に危険な行為になりました。
In fact, at that time there was a Poster talking about
実際、当時、次のようなポスターがありました。
Kissing can be dangerous
キスは危険なこともある
Then from this point of view, it means
この観点からすると、つまり、
Our hygiene keeps reminding you that
私たちの衛生管理は常に次のことを思い出させます
you have to be very careful
非常に注意しなければなりません
When you exchange physical property with others
他人と物的財産を交換するとき
Whether we drink from the same cup, right?
同じコップから飲むかどうかですよね？
or eat
または食べる
Or what kind of physical exchange
あるいはどのような物理的な交換ですか
It's an STD, right?
それは性感染症ですよね？
when you find out about sex
セックスについて知ったとき
You will also have a physical exchange
物理的な交換も行われます
What about the rise of hygiene?
衛生状態の向上についてはどうですか？
would make us very aware
私たちにとても気づかせてくれるだろう
material exchange between bodies
物体間の物質交換
There is also the social distance between people and the world
人と世界の間には社会的距離もあります
So this strengthens a concern between us and the human world
したがって、これは私たちと人間の世界との間の懸念を強化します
All of a sudden we're going to pay a lot of attention to this
突然、私たちはこれに多くの注意を払うことになります
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
The story we just told today
今日話したばかりの話
In fact, it is related to the personal hygiene in the middle of the night
実は、それは夜中の個人衛生に関係しています。
And what happened is closely related
そして、起こったことは密接に関係しています
Then I give these three examples to say
次に、これら 3 つの例を挙げて言います。
I just said these two things
この二つのことを言っただけです
What I just said is what I said earlier
私が今言ったことは前に言ったことです
Vice Miss' thoughts and Ge Chenghui's thoughts
副嬢の思いと葛成輝の思い
why close
なぜ閉じるのか
It is because in fact, when the three health systems are in operation
なぜなら、実際には、3つの医療制度が稼働しているときは、
It will invisibly strengthen certain identities
それは特定のアイデンティティを目に見えず強化します
So its original concern
だからそれは気にしただろう
it's about who we are
それは私たちが誰であるかについてです
so will be combined
それで結合されます
Then we go further with this
次に、これをさらに進めます
It can also be implemented when you are in epidemic prevention
防疫時にも実施可能
Remotely used or unused utensils
遠隔地で使用されたまたは未使用の器具
For example, didn't you just talk about that
たとえば、さっきそんな話をしたじゃないですか。
Isn't it very critical to take number two, right?
2番目を取ることは非常に重要ではないでしょうか?
anti-intermediate angle
反中間角
Anti-period is a pretty good thing that saves energy
アンチピリオドはエネルギーを節約する非常に良いことです
Because it is combined with the creation
創作と一体化しているので
Then everyone crowded on the resistance
それからみんなが抵抗に集まった
It is also the most efficient use of limited energy
また、限られたエネルギーを最も効率的に利用することもできます。
Just heat it up there after you finish cooking so that everyone can live
調理が終わったらその場で温めるだけでみんなが生きていける
But at this moment, he suddenly became an evil head of state.
しかしこの瞬間、彼は突然邪悪な国家元首になった
That is to say, it can spread the disease
つまり病気を蔓延させる可能性がある
Yes, just to the left is spreading the disease.
はい、左側が病気を広めています。
everyone together
みんな一緒に
But on the other hand
しかしその一方で、
It's not good to look at it from the perspective of four years.
4年間の視点で見るのは良くない。
which means to say
つまり言うこと
you have no privacy in this home
この家にはプライバシーがない
right
右
Every moment of your every second is seen by others
あなたのあらゆる瞬間が他人に見られています
you can't develop your personality
自分の個性を伸ばすことはできない
because you don't have a separate space
独立したスペースがないので
So this resistance is equivalent to changing
したがって、この抵抗は変化することと同じです
suddenly became a symbol
いつの間にかシンボルになった
It both infects germs and kills personalities
細菌に感染すると同時に人格をも殺す
Especially at home plus this room
特に家とこの部屋では
I like to close the windows
窓を閉めるのが好きです
It even said that it seems that your home is closed.
自宅が閉鎖されているようだとも言われました。
and you little kid in there
そしてそこにいる小さな子供よ
The one who was murdered developed this personality
殺された人はこの性格を発達させた
easy to get sick
病気になりやすい
It is the pursuit of hygiene and the pursuit of individuality
それは衛生の追求と個性の追求です
both are suppressed
どちらも抑制されている
In addition, I showed you one
さらに、一つご紹介させていただきました
personal hygiene cup
個人衛生カップ
This is the health experiment station of Peking Union Medical College Hospital
ここは北京連合医科大学病院の健康実験場です
A photo from 1935
1935 年の写真
That means
つまり、
from now on is to say
これからは言うことです
we just didn't talk
私たちは話さなかっただけです
Don't experience the exchange, right?
交流を体験してみませんか？
so start
それで始めてください
Everyone Has Everyone's Own Cup
誰もが自分のカップを持っています
even numbered
偶数の
So when you want to use
それで、使いたいときは、
you use your own cup
あなたは自分のカップを使用します
that in fact even in
それは実際には
It is also mentioned in the textbook
教科書にも載ってます
I use my own
私は自分のものを使用します
my own teacup
私自身のティーカップ
Then your method is
それからあなたの方法は
In this way you are reinforcing
このようにして強化します
You feel
あなたが感じる
you have to realize
あなたは気づかなければなりません
your contact with others
他の人との接触
actually very dangerous
実はとても危険です
so you gotta have your own teacup
だからあなたは自分のティーカップを持っていなければなりません
Then while you're using your own teacup
そして、自分のティーカップを使いながら、
Actually you too
実はあなたも
Invisibly educating you
実質的にあなたを教育する
It's because you don't like to use it with others
それは他人に使うのが嫌だからです
when you use it with others
他の人と一緒に使用する場合
even nauseated
吐き気すらする
you guys need to know what i mean
皆さんは私の言っている意味を知る必要があります
From this point of view
この観点から見ると
One he can both defend personal hygiene
両方とも個人の衛生状態を守ることができる人
It also strengthens a sense of individualism and a body
また、個性と身体の感覚を強化します。
It's just that you don't like sharing things with others.
それはあなたが他の人と物事を共有するのが好きではないというだけです。
What about Feijie and Hygiene Habits?
フェイジエと衛生習慣についてはどうですか?
Just like individualism is a kind of self-identity
個人主義が一種の自己アイデンティティであるのと同じように
equal to the mutual support of the two
二人の相互支援に等しい
So we usually talk about individualism
だから私たちはいつも個人主義について話します
is a value
値です
Or a way to protect your personal
または個人を保護する方法
law of power
力の法則
But in fact, it is also implemented in a body
しかし実際には、それはボディにも実装されています
you are like this
あなたはこんな人です
such a bodily sensation
そんな身体感覚
you have to use your own teacup
自分のティーカップを使用する必要があります
A condition that you don't want to mix with other people
他の人と関わりたくない状態
good
良い
So to say you see we can see now is to say
つまり、あなたは見える、私たちは今見えると言うのは、次のことです
I just said why these two colluded
この二人が共謀した理由を先ほど言いました
Why all the Chinese families
なぜ中国人家族全員が
authority as a problem
問題としての権威
serious personal harm
重大な人身被害
that on these two utensils
この2つの食器について
Their position is the same
彼らの立場は同じだ
Both sides criticized the
双方とも批判した
Then the use of personal hygiene cups will be encouraged, right?
そうすれば、個人用衛生カップの使用が奨励されるでしょう?
so that's it
それで終わりです
Those two are walking together again
あの二人はまた一緒に歩いてる
the worst the worst
最悪 最悪
Reasons for Defejah's Problems
デフェヤの問題の理由
In fact, it is a unique consensus system in China
実はこれは中国独自のコンセンサスシステムなのです
when you eat
食べるとき
Everyone confuses those chopsticks with whore roots
誰もがその箸を売春婦のルーツと混同する
into the same soup, right?
同じスープに入れますよね？
It's like saying you're exchanging this
これを交換しますと言っているようなものです
while you exchange saliva
唾液交換しながら
pass germs to each other
細菌を互いに伝え合う
That's what they thought the disease was
それが彼らが病気だと考えていたものです
the reason why it's so serious
それがとても深刻な理由
so this is the biggest challenge
これが最大の課題です
Then there is no way to solve a major problem
それでは大きな問題を解決する方法はありません
that is also at this time
それもこの時期に
So Wu Liande is the one
つまりウー・リアンデがその人だ
asked to come
来るように頼まれた
That is to say, to solve this problem
つまり、この問題を解決するには
Then the problem was
それから問題は
How serious did people think it was?
人々はそれがどれほど深刻だと考えていましたか？
You see, it's Kei Katsuragi who said again
ほら、また言ったのは葛城圭だよ
That is to say, facing this situation, he said
つまり、この状況に直面して、彼はこう言いました。
He said that when you go to another house
あなたが他の家に行くとき、彼は言いました
when still adopting the Chinese way of eating
まだ中国の食事法を採用しているとき
There's only one way you can defend yourself
自分を守る方法は一つしかない
it's you sneaking first
最初にこっそりしているのはあなたです
Hurry up and take out a scoop of each dish
急いで各料理をスプーンで取り出します
Then you don't eat it until someone else eats it
だったら他の人が食べるまで食べないでね
That's a policy of self-defense of last resort.
それは最終手段の自衛政策です。
If you deal with it properly, you can only be a little faster than others
適切に対処すれば、他の人より少しだけ早くなることができます
others may not see
他の人は見えないかもしれない
It was you who secretly ate first
こっそり先に食べたのは君だった
so you can feel in this
それであなたはこれで感じることができます
as far as he is concerned
彼に関する限り
how much he believes
彼はどれだけ信じているのか
The disease brought about by this consensus
この合意がもたらす病気
is he would mind such a solution
彼はそのような解決策を考えますか
that this
これは
yes you can watch
はい、見ることができます
You can see where he is absolutely in danger.
彼の絶対的な危険がどこにあるのかがわかります。
good
良い
then in this case
それからこの場合は
equal to why we just said
先ほど言った理由と同じです
Wuliande will come to create this
Wuliandeがこれを作りに来ます
It is because he is facing such a predicament
それは彼がそのような苦境に直面しているからです
that is
あれは
every day when everyone is eating
毎日みんなが食事をしているときに
equal to one of the most important
最も重要なものの 1 つに等しい
Ways and channels of infection
感染経路と感染経路
right
右
how to solve this
これをどうやって解決するか
So he came up with three possibilities
そこで彼は3つの可能性を思いつきました
What about the first possibility?
最初の可能性についてはどうでしょうか？
take-out tense
就採取分時制
just like westerners
西洋人と同じように
then you are going
それならあなたは行き​​ます
like a personal hygiene cup, right?
個人用衛生カップのようなものですよね？
Divide the dishes first, everyone eats everyone's
まず料理を分けて、全員が全員の分を食べます
so we don't exchange
だから私たちは交換しません
Exchanging that drool won't spread the germs either.
そのよだれを交換しても細菌が広がることはありません。
what did he say
彼が何を言ったの
He doesn't think it's a good way to eat Chinese food
彼は中華料理を食べるのが良い方法だとは思っていない
He is Malaysian Chinese
彼はマレーシア系中国人です
that is so you see
それはわかります
he makes the decision now
彼は今決断する
On the one hand, it is a matter of hygiene
一方で、それは衛生上の問題です
On the one hand, it will have a profound impact on
一方で、それは深刻な影響を与えるだろう
the way we eat in the future, right?
私たちの将来の食事方法ですよね？
It even means that the relationship between us and others
それは私たちと他者との関係さえも意味します
He said it's not a good way
彼はそれは良い方法ではないと言いました
but he didn't make it clear
しかし彼はそれを明確にしなかった
Why does he think it's not a good way
なぜ彼はそれが良い方法ではないと思うのですか
Instead, I was in a 1950
代わりに、私は1950年にいた
The doctor in Taiwan wrote that
台湾の医師はこう書いています。
Why does he think this is not a good way
なぜ彼はこれが良い方法ではないと思うのでしょうか
He said you have to eat whole fish because of Chinese food
彼は中華料理だから魚を丸ごと食べなければならないと言った
whole chicken whole duck
丸ごとの鶏肉 丸ごとのアヒル
It's like dividing the rotten mess on everyone's plate
腐った散らかったものを全員の皿に分けるようなものだ
not good
良くない
So he thinks it's not a good way
だから彼はそれは良い方法ではないと考えている
so this is actually quite interesting
これは実際には非常に興味深いです
I quite agree with him
私も彼に全く同意します
It's a good thing we didn't adopt this food sharing system
このフードシェアリングシステムを採用しなくて良かった
For more than five years, I said that this is not a good way.
私は5年以上、これは良い方法ではないと言い続けてきました。
What about the second one? He strengthened it.
2 番目のものはどうですか? 彼はそれを強化しました。
Everyone should have two pairs of chopsticks
誰もが二組の箸を持つべきです
So you just have a pair of chopsticks
それで、あなたは箸を持っているだけです
For example, you say that I am catching that fish now.
たとえば、私は今その魚を釣っていると言います。
You pick up that fish with a chopstick
あなたはその魚を箸で持ち上げます
put it in
中に入れて
You change another chopstick
別の箸に変えると
come in your mouth
あなたの口に入ってきてください
Then he said another pair of chopsticks
それから彼は別の箸を言いました。
you should use red
赤を使うべきです
That's like a reminder that it's dangerous
それは危険であることを思い出させるようなものです
just use it on yourself
自分にだけ使ってください
But he said it's not a good way
でも彼はそれは良い方法ではないと言いました
In fact, it is said that I was the one just now
実はさっきまで私だったそうです
The guest mentioned Song Meiling
ゲストはソン・メイリンについて言及した
It is said that Song Meiling's family used these two pairs of chopsticks
ソン・メイリンさんの家族はこの2組の箸を使っていたと言われています。
It's not a good way to say it in five years
5年後に言うのは良くない
Because of his own trial results
彼自身の試験結果のせいで
I found it very easy to get confused
非常に混乱しやすいことがわかりました
It's the slowness, you can't figure it out
それは遅さだ、君には理解できないんだ
Which pair is which pair of chopsticks
どのペアはどの箸ですか
That is in this context
それはこの文脈で言えば
He finally said he designed this
彼はついにこれを自分がデザインしたと言いました
Hydrogenic Chinese Dining Table
水素中華食卓
invent this
これを発明する
In fact, this is to cooperate with the male and female pools
実はこれ、男女プールで協力するためなんです
It has a detailed description of how the plate is to be made
プレートの作り方が詳しく書いてあります
so it really thinks it invented it
だから本当に自分が発明したと思っているんだ
Then the key point is that it should be combined with the male block and the female pool
そこでポイントとなるのが、男性ブロックと女性プールとの組み合わせです。
So what is the purpose of this plate?
それで、このプレートの目的は何ですか？
because if you don't have this plate
このプレートがなかったら
For dishes farther away, you can’t get the male and female pools, right?
遠いお皿だと、男女のプールが手に入らないですよね？
If you have this plate, you can put it
このお皿があれば置いてもいいですね
Turn in front of you and follow the male and female pool
正面を向き、男女のプールに沿って進みます
you can use
使用できます
So in a situation like this
それで、このような状況では
it thinks it designed this
これをデザインしたと思われます
Solved a hygiene problem
衛生問題を解決しました
And at the same time it can
そして同時にそれは可能です
Solved the problem of sanitation
衛生面の問題を解決しました
But it's not fully remodeled
でも完全には改造されてないよ
innate way of eating
生まれつきの食べ方
the relationship between me and a person
私と人との関係
So it's very proud to think it's a
だから、それがだと思うのはとても誇りです
combined with a traditional way of dining
伝統的な食事方法と組み合わせた
and an indigenous innovation of modern hygiene principles
そして現代の衛生原則の先住民の革新
so in other words
つまり、言い換えれば
Even when you face this hygiene challenge
この衛生上の課題に直面しても
You can still create a way
まだ道は作れる
To protect some original social relations
本来の社会関係を守るため
you eat full chinese food
あなたはお腹いっぱい中華料理を食べます
Then it means that everyone hangs out and eats together.
それから、みんなで集まって一緒に食事をするということになります。
In fact, we put this matter
実際、私たちはこの問題を提起しました
The cultural history of 1924 is actually a
1924 年の文化史は実際には
You may feel small now
今は自分が小さく感じるかもしれない
But it was a big deal at the time
でも当時は大変なことになった
Because it affects people's social relations
それは人々の社会関係に影響を与えるからです
For example, let me show you a picture
たとえば、写真を見せてみましょう
This picture is a round table in Japan on Tatami
この写真は日本の畳の上の円卓です
right
右
you may want to
したいかもしれません
It's also a modern invention
これも現代の発明です
When the Japanese eat at the table
日本人がテーブルで食事をするとき
each eats his own
それぞれが自分の分を食べる
Then came the introduction of Western civilization
その後、西洋文明が導入されました
they get a concept
彼らはコンセプトを得る
That is to say the definition of a Happy Family
つまり、幸せな家族の定義です
Just want everyone to eat together
みんなで一緒に食べたいだけ
no such words
そんな言葉はありません
no real family feeling
本当の家族感がない
That's why I invented this table
それがこのテーブルを発明した理由です
So the story I just told is that
それで、私が今話した話は、
Actually our
実は私たちの
Various difficulties encountered in order to prevent the epidemic
感染症の流行を防ぐために直面​​するさまざまな困難
Artifacts created by concepts
コンセプトによって生み出された成果物
and that bodily sensation
そしてその身体感覚
have profoundly affected us
私たちに大きな影響を与えた
that's a
それは
So we may often
それで私たちはしばしば
didn't realize
気づかなかった
But as long as we think about today, if we
しかし、今日のことを考える限り、もし私たちが
no longer eating on that plate
もうその皿で食べない
But if everyone gets a share
でも、全員が分け前をもらったら
Our lives may really have changed a lot
私たちの生活は本当に大きく変わってしまったかもしれない
That's what I'm going to report to you today.
それが今日私が皆さんに報告するテーマです。
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you so much Mr. Ray
レイさん、本当にありがとうございました
give a very good speech
とても良いスピーチをする
I believe that everyone has gained as much as I have.
私と同じように、誰もが多くのものを得たと信じています。
then we were
そのとき私たちは
The top ten guests who asked questions
質問をしたゲスト上位10名
we have prepared a beautiful little gift
素敵な小さな贈り物をご用意しました
That's because a few friends have already asked questions
すでに何人かの友人が質問しているためです
Then we are open Q&A now
それでは、今から質疑応答を開始します
And as long as it's the top ten
そしてそれがトップ10である限り
We have this in our homestay
私たちのホームステイにはこれがあります
Speaking of we are two or three questions your answer
私たちについて言えば、2、3 つの質問があります、あなたの答えは
It's all good, okay, okay
大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫
Okay two or three
わかりました 2 つか 3 つ
good good good
良い良い良い
Like this, please answer again
このように、もう一度答えてください
Are we the first
私たちが最初ですか
In the first round we collect two or three questions
最初のラウンドでは 2 つまたは 3 つの質問が収集されます
Professor Lei, have you ever visited South Korea
レイ先生、韓国を訪れたことがありますか？
Then the Koreans eat
じゃあ韓国人も食べるよ
How are their habits different from those of the Chinese?
彼らの習慣は中国人の習慣とどう違うのでしょうか？
Or is it different from how Taiwanese eat?
それとも台湾人の食事とは違うのでしょうか？
Recently, the epidemic in South Korea has been soaring
最近、韓国での感染が急増しています
terrible
ひどい
Thanks
ありがとう
ok thanks for coming
わかりました、来てくれてありがとう
Hello Professor Lei
こんにちは、レイ先生
I find it very interesting the way you use that inference
その推論の使い方がとても興味深いと思います
Then discuss which family becomes a most bonded one
次に、どの家族が最も絆が深いことが判明したかについて話し合います
Then there is a conclusion that the transformation of the traditional Chinese family is a process before pathology
そして、伝統的な中国家族の変容は病理以前の過程であるという結論が得られる。
If we take an inference like yours
もし私たちがあなたのような推論をするなら
And compared to what the West is talking about
そして、西側諸国が話していることと比較すると、
Abandoned festivals are a disease of civilization caused by modernization
放棄された祭りは近代化が引き起こした文明の病である
So is it under such a history in the West?
では、西洋ではそのような歴史があるのでしょうか？
There is also such a thing as industrialization and urbanization
工業化と都市化というものもあります
The condition of a phenomenal society that also pathologizes it
現象的な社会が病理化している状態
or there is such a discourse produced
あるいはそのような言説が生み出されている
because what we see seems to be an opposite result
私たちが見ているものは反対の結果のように見えるからです
It is they who want to promote the economy instead
代わりに経済を促進したいのは彼らです
Then caused a second wave of accelerated industrialization
その後、加速する工業化の第二波を引き起こした
yes
はい
Thanks
ありがとう
that there was no socialist country
社会主義国なんてなかった
So rise up at that time
だからその時は立ち上がれ
yes
はい
Thanks
ありがとう
ok maybe one more question
OK、もう一つ質問してもいいですか
Let's ask Lei Shao to answer together
レイ・シャオに一緒に答えてもらいましょう
come please
来てください
It is because of this economic factor that the dissemination of scrap joints
スクラップジョイントの普及はこの経済的要因によるものです。
Is it possible that
可能ですか？
The Great Depression of 1929
1929 年の大恐慌
And that leads to saying that people start to have this kind of thinking
そしてそれは、人々がこの種の考え方を持ち始めるということにつながります
However, it was discovered that China
ところが、中国が判明したのは、
was not affected by the events of 1929
1929 年の出来事の影響を受けなかった
think about family
家族のことを考える
To infer that China's puzzling box came from the family
中国の不可解な箱は家族から来ていると推測するには
rather than economically
経済的というよりも
thanks for your questions
ご質問ありがとうございます
In terms of this last question
この最後の質問に関して言えば、
In fact, it is considered to be a social problem.
実際、社会問題とも考えられています。
You see what I mentioned in the title of the book just now
先ほど本のタイトルで述べたことがわかりますか
19th century France
19世紀のフランス
It actually happened at the end of the 19th century
それは19世紀末に実際に起こった
So in fact, everyone knows that at the end of the 19th century
実際、19 世紀末には誰もが知っています。
a lot of socialist ideas
社会主義的な考えがたくさんある
It's all started, right?
すべては始まりましたね？
I think it's social structure
それは社会構造だと思う
In fact, it is very harmful to human health
実際、人間の健康に非常に有害です
So in fact, it should not need to go to 1929
したがって、実際には 1929 年まで遡る必要はないはずです。
The Great Depression Happened
大恐慌が起こった
Already happened at the end of the 19th century
19世紀末にはすでに起こっていた
Probably such a situation
たぶんそういう状況
The question you asked just now is a very good question
今の質問はとても良い質問です
Indeed
それはそう
that is
あれは
So what we mean by civilization disease is actually very contradictory.
つまり、文明病という言葉が意味するものは、実は非常に矛盾しているのです。
Because civilization is inherently good, right?
文明は本質的に良いものだからですよね？
But I feel that civilization may bring disease
でも文明は病気をもたらすかもしれないと思う
So in fact, from this point of view, it means
実際、この観点からすると、それは次のことを意味します
As we just said, for example
先ほど述べたように、たとえば
The establishment of the 8-hour working hour system per day, etc.
1日8時間労働制の確立など
equal to this question
この質問に等しい
The problems brought about by the civilization of media
メディア文明がもたらす問題
Indeed some people regard it as a
確かにそれを次のように考える人もいます
just this article
このテキストだけ
as a text
テキストとして
critique of civilization
文明批判
you are right
あなたが正しいです
Another well-known response to the so-called disease of civilization is
いわゆる文明の病に対するもう一つのよく知られた反応は次のとおりです。
neurasthenia
神経衰弱
Of course, these were probably the two most famous diseases at the time.
もちろん、これらはおそらく当時最も有名な 2 つの病気でした。
that is to say, people would think
つまり人々はこう思うだろう
Actually you should be able to trace back to our civilization
実際、私たちの文明まで遡ることができるはずです
brought about by a negative place
ネガティブな場所によってもたらされる
so you are right
だからあなたは正しい
Then you just talked about a situation in South Korea
それからあなたは今韓国の状況について話しました
Actually, I dare not say that I understand so well
実は、わかっているとはあえて言えないのですが、
the state of their meals
彼らの食事の様子
Then
それから
You start by telling me that I can't remember
あなたは私に思い出せないと言い始めます
I can only
私にできるのは
I probably remember my first time
たぶん初めてのことを覚えている
I just got this research result
たった今こんな研究結果が出ました
When sharing with a Korean medical historian
韓国の医学史家と共有する場合
He said why the Koreans didn't invent this thing
彼はなぜ韓国人がこれを発明しなかったのかと言った
So he probably felt there was some kind of relationship
だから彼はおそらく何らかの関係があると感じたでしょう
But I don't know that much about Korea
でも、韓国についてはあまり詳しくありません
to answer this question
この質問に答えるために
Excuse me
すみません
I would like to ask this is the part about this study
お聞きしたいのは、この研究に関する部分です
Is there any data found later?
後で何かデータが見つかったのでしょうか？
Said that after using this stall
この屋台を利用した後、こう言いました
Some reduction related data of FJH
FJHの削減関連データの一部
Are there statistics?
統計はありますか？
or is this a
それともこれは
One of our conclusions from the previous
前回の結論の 1 つは、
A food that can still be seen
今でも見られる食べ物
But maybe when collecting data
でもおそらくデータを収集するときに
not that much research
あまり研究されていない
I don't believe there is such a Fei Jiehe
こんなフェイ・ジェヘがいるとは信じられない
This data actually reduces
このデータは実際に減少します
Is there this connection
このつながりはありますか
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
any left
少し残っている
come here sir
ここに来てください、先生
Huang Peiren
黄培仁
Huang Peiren ask the teacher for advice
黄培仁は先生にアドバイスを求める
that now a group meal
それは今ではグループ食事です
Fuji-Canada Group
フジカナダグループ
Everyone said big dinner
みんなは豪華なディナーを言いました
it's a big meal
それは大きな食事です
it's a buffet style
ビュッフェスタイルです
such a
そのような
wrong work
間違った仕事
Will it change later
後で変わるのかな
this whole one
これ全部
one of the dining habits
食生活の一つ
Way
方式
even brought home
家に持ち帰っても
I bring it home like this
こんな感じで持って帰ります
Thanks
ありがとう
any left
少し残っている
we can three questions
3つの質問ができます
Then please this
それでは、これをお願いします
Director Lei, Mr. Lei
レイ監督、レイさん
Listen to our answer Line
私たちの答えを聞いてください
I'm Hou
私はホウです
idea is to say
アイデアは言うことです
During the teacher's speech just now, you can see
先ほどの先生のお話の中で、
That is to say, the relationship between people and diseases is from
つまり、人と病気の関係は、
national power
国力
start to get deeper into the individual
個人の中に深く入り込み始める
and remove people from the family
そして家族から人々を排除する
Freed from traditional family
伝統的な家族から解放される
and then controlled by state power
その後は国家権力によって管理される
Did he also affect the later 49 years later
彼はその後の49年にも影響を与えたのでしょうか？
Chinese Communist Party in
中国共産党
Some views on medical care in this process in China
中国におけるこのプロセスにおける医療に関するいくつかの見解
How will it change that's my first question
どう変わるのか、それが私の最初の質問です
The second question I look at from the context of European history
ヨーロッパの歴史の文脈から見た2番目の質問
words mean
言葉の意味
From the cross tank written by that country autumn in the past
昔、あの国の秋が書いたクロスタンクより
to the one written by fukuguchi
福口さんが書いたものへ
The history of madness books have about the so-called wind power guys
狂気の歴史の本には、いわゆる風力発電の人たちの話が出てくる
like being locked in bed
ベッドに閉じ込められているような
Plus it's like
さらに、それは次のようなものです
Thomas Mann in his
トーマス・マンの著書
Zauberberg's novel also describes
ザウバーバーグの小説にも次のように書かれています。
Fei Jiehe's patients
費潔和の患者
They are usually a rich bourgeois
彼らは通常裕福なブルジョワです
locked in a
閉じ込められた
A very luxurious mountain on a Swiss mountain
スイスの山にあるとても贅沢な山
such a process
そのようなプロセス
Then I don't know what the teacher thinks about it
じゃあ先生がどう思ってるかは分からないけど
Such a change or how to be honest about such a phenomenon
そのような変化、またはそのような現象について正直になる方法
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes Yes
はいはい
that
それか
Thank you for your question
ご質問ありがとうございます
First
初め
the first question you asked me
あなたが私に尋ねた最初の質問
to be honest
実を言うと
i didn't see
見ませんでした
I don't see relevant research statistics
関連する調査統計が見当たりません
And in fact Mandroid
そして実はマンアンドロイド
in this story
この物語の中で
In fact, this should follow
実際、これは次のようになります
The male and female pool
男女別プール
right
右
But I actually don't know the male pool and the female pool
でも実は男子プールと女子プールが分からないんです
How popular was it at the time
当時どれくらい流行ってたんだろう
and frankly
そして率直に言って
I
私
The first picture I just showed you
先ほどお見せした最初の写真
In fact, in 1965 in that China Town in the United States
実は1965年、アメリカのあのチャイナタウンで
that is
あれは
now likely
おそらく
Five years did invent the dinner plate in 1915
1915年にこのディナープレートが実際に発明されるまでに5年かかりました
but it didn't really catch on
しかしそれはあまり普及しませんでした
when it became popular
それが人気になったとき
In fact it is the result of restaurants adopting
実際、それはレストランが採用した結果です
Well I now know that one was developed in Japan in 1930
さて、私は今、それが1930年代に日本で開発されたことを知っています
another one is this
もう一つはこれです
This is thought to have become popular later in China Town
これは後にチャイナタウンで流行したと考えられています
So in fact, when it became popular later, it didn’t follow
実際、その後流行ったときは続かなかったのですが、
Follow the male and female pool
男女のプールをフォローしてください
So that impact may be more limited
そのため、その影響はより限定的になる可能性があります
So this your question is
それで、あなたの質問はこれです
It's a very good and scientific question
とても良い科学的な質問です
Unfortunately we didn't
残念ながら、そうではありませんでした
There is no way to trace this development
この展開を追跡する方法はありません
and then just another
それからもう一つ
Is it the group meal you mentioned?
それはあなたが言ったグループの食事ですか？
Actually that's an interesting question
実際、それは興味深い質問です
that is
あれは
But now I also have a moment
でも、私にも今は時間があります
don't know how to answer
どう答えていいかわからない
Just saying the things we can tell is that
ただ言えることだけを言うと、
I think this is one of my speeches today
これは今日の私のスピーチの一つだと思います
pretty big spindle
かなり大きなスピンドル
That is to say, after the germ theory became popular
つまり、細菌理論が普及した後、
It's actually very powerful
実はとても強力なんです
that is, we might think
つまり、私たちはこう思うかもしれません
It's just a way to control the disease
それは病気を制御するための単なる方法です
But it actually got into our lives
しかし、それは実際に私たちの生活に入り込んだ
very detailed design
非常に詳細なデザイン
For example, like all the food we buy now
たとえば、私たちが今買っているすべての食べ物と同じように、
Almost all have plastic packaging, right?
ほとんどすべてがプラスチックパッケージですよね？
basically you don't trust any
基本的に何も信用していない
food without packaging
包装されていない食品
because you feel the potential to contaminate
汚染の可能性を感じているからです
This is also the situation after the germ theory became popular.
これは細菌説が流行した後の状況でもある。
But I want to eat in a group situation
でもグループで食事したい
In fact, for example, whether in the army or in a factory
実際、例えば軍隊であろうと工場であろうと、
That must have an interesting history worth studying
それは研究する価値のある興味深い歴史を持っているに違いない
Then I can't do anything right now
それなら今は何も出来ない
don't know that much
そんなに知りません
so no way to answer your good question
だからあなたの良い質問に答える方法はない
add more teacher
さらに先生を追加
That is to say, in ancient times, a fair or a meeting of property officials
つまり、古代の博覧会や財産管理者の会議で
change collective
集団を変える
right
右
It's also a big bunch
それも大きな束です
That ancient group of bamboo flowers one by one
あの古代の竹の花群が一つ一つ
or sub-station
または変電所
will it be
そうなるだろうか
In ancient times, there were many infectious diseases
古代には伝染病が多かった
yes
はい
would cause a big one
大きな問題を引き起こすだろう
An explosion of contagion
感染爆発
right
右
Also such an important one
とても大切なものでもあります
yes
はい
a stunned look
唖然とした表情
Not possible to be
ありえない
But that's the point of today's story
しかし、それが今日の話のポイントです
that's when you won't doubt
そのときは疑うことはありません
passed on to you by people close to you
あなたの身近な人から伝えられた
But now you're highly skeptical
しかし今、あなたは非常に懐疑的です
people around you pass it on to you
周りの人がそれをあなたに伝える
You may even suspect that your family passed it on to you
家族からうつされたのではないかと疑うこともあるかもしれません
So much so that it changed one of you and your family
それはあなたとあなたの家族の一人を変えたほどです
Look at the trust relationship of the people around you
周りの人の信頼関係を見てみよう
Probably so. For intimacy.
おそらくそうでしょう。親密さのために。
hello then
こんにちは、それでは
Your question first is very good
最初の質問はとても良いです
In fact, it was later in 1949
実際、それは1949年の後半でした
The Communist Party of China says
中国共産党は言う
Fei Jie and is a society
フェイジエとは社会です
And he said before
そして彼は前にこう言いました
The former capitalist Kuomintang
かつての資本家国民党
don't care about everyone
みんなは気にしないでください
So you never really have to fix the problem
したがって、実際に問題を解決する必要はありません
So the way they did it later was in the factory
つまり、彼らが後でそれを行ったのは工場でのことでした
to build that
それを構築するために
that
それか
equal to field one
フィールド 1 と等しい
Then come to help with this problem
それならこの問題を手伝ってください
So this is later
ということで、これはまた後ほど
That is, the Communist Party of China very much believes that
つまり、中国共産党は次のことを強く信じているのだ。
They are different from the KMT's approach
彼らは国民党のアプローチとは異なる
They are very highly publicized
彼らは非常に宣伝されています
This is the side of Social Disease
これが社会病の側面です
That is the only continuation of the period of the Kuomintang
それが国民党時代の唯一の継続である
is for
のためです
Dealing with the problem of spitting
唾吐きの問題に対処する
So it turned out to be a major vice
それで、それは重大な悪徳であることが判明しました
But that's another story
でもそれはまた別の話
But they do put a lot of emphasis on
しかし、彼らが非常に重視しているのは、
This is a social disease
これは社会病です
in a capitalist society
資本主義社会では
unwilling to admit this social disease
この社会病を認めたくない
because you don't want to improve
改善したくないから
That is to say, a living environment for workers
つまり、働く人の生活環境
Probably such a situation
たぶんそういう状況
And then you later Thomsman's argument
そして、後でトムズマンの議論
I didn't understand that question very well
その質問はよくわかりませんでした
can you explain more
もっと説明してもらえますか
I didn't understand the second part very well
後半はよく分かりませんでした
The second part I want to ask is to say
私が聞きたい2番目の部分は、次のことです。
The old four don't treat that European member
古い4人はそのヨーロッパ人メンバーを扱いません
disease management point
疾病管理のポイント
yes
はい
Because in these novels, for example, Stan
なぜなら、これらの小説では、たとえばスタンが
Or like in that Fuko's book
あるいはあの風子の本のように
Or like in Thomasman's novel
あるいはトーマスマンの小説のように
I thought of some phenomena about Fei Jiehe
費継和に関するいくつかの現象を考えてみました
if go to control
コントロールに行く場合
How will he treat his phenomenon
彼は自分の現象をどう扱うだろうか
I don't know how the teacher treats this problem
先生がこの問題についてどう考えているかわかりません
yes
はい
Fei Jiehe is sure you have heard of it
フェイ・ジェヘさんはきっと聞いたことがあるでしょう
Is there a Chinese art book?
中国のアートブックはありますか？
It was written by Su Zhenchang Pagoda
蘇真昌塔が書いたものです。
Unice as the metaphor, right?
比喩としてのユニスですよね？
That is Fei Jiehe is a special one, that is to say
つまり、フェイ・ジエヘは特別な存在だということです。
There are many descriptions in the literature
文献には多くの記述がある
because it is a chronic disease
慢性疾患だから
That is to say, and you can live a long time with this
つまり、これで長生きできるということです
Then each has a lot of descriptions
そして、それぞれにたくさんの説明があります
And once romanticized by that
そしてかつてはそれによってロマンチックになった
right
右
So the childbirth thing I just talked about
さて、先ほどお話しした出産のことですが、
It's not just China
中国だけじゃないよ
Even in the West there are such descriptions
西洋にもそういう記述はある
That is, after the people who can talk about Feigehe
それは、Feigehe について語れる人々の後です。
That is to say, even women's faces will turn red
つまり女性でも顔が赤くなるのです。
Yes, then there is a stronger
はい、それならもっと強いのがあります
more delicate sensibility
より繊細な感性
and love of life
そして人生への愛
Then there are many love stories
それからラブストーリーもたくさんあります
Then this one originally had such an image
じゃあこれも元々そういうイメージだったんだな
So it's actually quite a positive image.
ですから、実際にはかなりポジティブなイメージです。
But so it's also about theater theory
しかし、それは演劇理論にも関係します
After the theatrical theory came
演劇理論が登場した後
when you see him you see a
彼を見ると、
very different him
とても違う彼
just because you thought
あなたが思ったからといって
Because when the heroine was in the lungs
ヒロインが肺にいたときだから
In fact, when you are not contagious concepts
実際、あなたが伝染性の概念を持っていないときは、
you might think it's a
と思うかも知れません
a disease within him, right?
彼の中にある病気ですね
so you might even think
それであなたも思うかもしれません
While he sells his body
彼が体を売っている間、
His inspiration even goes so far as to say
彼のインスピレーションは次のようにも言えます。
The sensibility is enhanced
感性が磨かれる
love life more
人生をもっと愛する
But when you see him later
しかし、後で彼に会ったとき、
when it becomes a sick head
頭がおかしくなったとき
It's not easy to romanticize anymore
もうロマンチックにするのは簡単ではない
So you see, it turns into saying
なるほど、こう言うことになります。
that you are related to the poor
あなたは貧しい人々と関係があるということ
This is also a very important point, right?
これも非常に重要なポイントですよね？
It's that part that transforms
変形するのはその部分です
Well, it's actually quite a complicated process.
まあ、実際にはかなり複雑なプロセスです。
Because this disease is very long
この病気はとても長引くので、
So there are a lot of people with a lot of related descriptions
関連する記述がたくさんある人がたくさんいるので、
The simplest thing to say is to say
最も簡単なことはこう言うことです
At one point he experienced a
ある時点で彼は、
A process of being romanticized
ロマンチックになるプロセス
later became considered a poor man's disease
後に貧乏人の病気とみなされるようになった
even a social issue
社会問題でも
roughly like this
大体こんな感じ
right
右
Thank you Mr. Lei
レイさん、ありがとう
any left
少し残っている
we still have a little time
まだ少し時間があります
opportunity for him to come
彼が来る機会
Feel sorry
気の毒だと思う
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
I'm bope from the law firm
私は法律事務所のボープです
Then I have a question is
それから質問がありますが、
The teacher just had a powerpoint
先生はちょうどパワーポイントを持っていました
There are three identities mentioned
3人の正体が言及されている
Does the teacher want to explain through these three identities
先生はこの 3 つのアイデンティティを通して説明したいのですか?
Why is the epidemic prevention from a scientific point of view
なぜ防疫が科学的な観点から行われるのか
That's another aspect of individualism
それは個人主義のもう一つの側面です
That leads to not asking children to criticize the concept of family
それは子供たちに家族の概念を批判するよう求めないことにつながります
The first of these, identity, is national sovereignty.
その最初のアイデンティティは国家主権です。
I remember correctly, I was thinking
正確に覚えています、私は考えていました
What about national sovereignty because it sounds like a
国家主権についてはどうですか？
totalitarian concept of a society
全体主義的な社会概念
how could cause
どのようにして引き起こせるのか
It can be explained that behind the promotion of individualism
個人主義の推進の背景には次のようなものがあると説明できる。
Identity
身元
yeah sorry i miss me
はい、ごめんなさい、会いたいです
It's just that what I just said was not very clear
ただ、私が今言ったことはあまり明確ではありませんでした
In fact, it was just that
実はそれだけだったんです
What I said on that slide is actually
そのスライドで私が言ったことは実際には
We follow the prevention and control of this infectious disease
私たちはこの感染症の予防と制御に従います
I just introduced three different systems, right?
先ほど3つの異なるシステムを紹介しましたね。
that each different system
それぞれ異なるシステムであること
Makes you pay different attention to dangerous boundaries
危険な境界線に対して異なる注意を払うようになります
that this focus on borders
これは国境に焦点を当てているということ
promotes a certain identity
特定のアイデンティティを促進する
When isolation is easy
隔離が容易な場合
That border is not on the skin
その境界線は皮膚上にありません
right
右
Not between people and the environment
人と環境の間ではなく
not between people
人と人の間ではなく
This is the second and third
これは2番目と3番目です
The first one is spatial
一つ目は空間的なもの
right
右
What about the spatial result?
空間的な結果はどうでしょうか?
that is
あれは
So in fact, what is strengthened is
では実際に強化されるのは、
I am your person in this space
私はこの空間にいるあなたの人です
with that space of your human world
あなたの人間世界のその空間で
different different
違う違う
and i'm going to separate from you
そして私はあなたから離れるつもりです
And I think the danger comes from there
そして危険はそこから来ると思います
So it's not an individualistic identification
だからそれは個人的な識別ではない
but a collective identity
しかし、集合的なアイデンティティ
like
好き
Actually I think like
実際、私は次のように考えています
Taiwan right?
台湾ですよね？
right now you feel like saying
今あなたはこう言いたい気分です
we are
私たちです
We have put the whole world
私たちは全世界を置きました
Everywhere is considered a dangerous place
どこでも危険な場所とみなされます
only we are safe
私たちだけが安全です
right
右
The reason why this can be successful
これが成功できる理由
with us as a sovereign state
主権国家として私たちとともに
manageable borders
扱いやすい国境
right
右
And at the same time, it will make you feel more strongly
そして同時に、より強く感じるでしょう
The things around you are originally yours
あなたの周りにあるものは、もともとあなたのものです
for example
例えば
We really wanted to support Hong Kong
私たちは香港を本当に応援したかったのです
But now you can't help but see it as
しかし今ではそう見えずにはいられません。
a dangerous source
危険な情報源
it's just outside your homeland
それはあなたの故郷のすぐ外にあります
You are isolated from it
あなたはそこから孤立している
This is also imperceptibly
これもいつの間にか
It is a common interest of the people within this regime who can exercise sovereign control
主権的統制を行使できるのは、この政権内の人々の共通の利益である
right
右
You have common interests and your common security is protected
あなたには共通の利益があり、共通の安全が守られています
People who are all within this line are united
このライン内にいる人々は団結します
so it's really not personal
だからそれは本当に個人的なものではない
but a situation within a sovereign state
しかし、主権国家内の状況
Then the question you mentioned is actually
それで、あなたが話していることは実際には
That is also a main axis that I want to share with you today.
それが今日皆さんにお伝えしたい主軸でもあります。
that is
あれは
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
We would have thought of this as a completely neutral treatment of disease.
私たちはこれを病気の完全に中立的な治療法だと考えていたでしょう。
these sanitation systems
これらの衛生システム
It will invisibly strengthen certain boundaries
それは目に見えない特定の境界を強化します
and then make us even develop certain habits
そして私たちに特定の習慣を身につけさせます
then make our impact on us
そして私たちに影響を与えます
In fact, it is far more than a temporary control of a disease.
実際、それは病気を一時的に制御するだけではありません。
a far-reaching impact of
～の広範囲にわたる影響
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
Thanks
ありがとう
any left
少し残っている
Come
来て
the professor i want to ask a question
教授、質問したいのですが
just now
ちょうど今
When someone asked a question just now, it was mentioned that
先ほど誰かが質問したときに、次のようなことが言われました。
It is after World War II if the treatment fee is resolved.
治療費が解決すれば戦後です。
Just after the card is drawn out
カードを抜いた直後
what i want to ask is
私が聞きたいのは
just before the card is traced
カードをなぞる直前
The treatment of health experts in the event is to only put those
イベントにおける医療専門家の扱いは、これらの者のみを対象とします。
It's like improving ventilation or poor light production.
換気を改善したり、光の生成を悪くしたりするようなものです。
or the home quarantine you just mentioned
あるいは先ほど言った自宅隔離
As far as those methods are concerned, my own thoughts are
それらの方法に関する限り、私自身の考えは次のとおりです。
only to slow down the rate of infection
感染速度を遅らせるためだけ
for those already infected
すでに感染している人にとっては
Health experts at the time were
当時の健康専門家は、
what method to take
どのような方法をとるか
let them just
彼らにそのままにしておいてください
is healed or
治ったり、
what kind of therapy
どのような治療法ですか
people who are already infected
すでに感染している人
In fact, it can only be sent to a nursing home.
実際には、老人ホームにのみ送ることができます。
can do very limited
できることは非常に限られている
From our perspective today, it is impossible to cure
今日の私たちの視点から見ると、治療することは不可能です
right
右
Just let him fix the itch
彼にかゆみを治してもらいましょう
And then there's the sun
そして、太陽があります
then what else
他に、次に何を
Anyway, from our perspective today, it’s like what you said
とにかく、今日の私たちの視点からすると、あなたが言ったことのようです
None of them are effective treatments
どれも効果的な治療法ではない
just heal
ただ癒すだけ
it's a treat
それはご褒美です
yes that's the case
はい、そうです
yes
はい
we eat
私たちは食べる
Not all Japanese dishes are like this
すべての日本料理がこうであるわけではありません
dinner plate
ディナープレート
everyone eats their own
みんな自分で食べます
Then when eating Chinese food, everyone will not be together
そうすると中華料理を食べるときにみんなが集まらなくなる
even that
それでも
that has that
それはそれがある
rotating
回転する
Everyone at the dining table is still
食卓にいるみんなはまだ
Can eating this together reflect that
これを一緒に食べるとそれが反映されるでしょうか
Japanese watermelon layers
日本のスイカの層
Influence of Freedom of Thought
思想の自由の影響
than China
中国よりも
come deep
深く来てください
or
また
China
中国
Even if China
中国にしても
With the emergence of this revolving dining table
この回転ダイニングテーブルの登場により
Did it mean that liberalism was under the impact of the main ideas?
自由主義が主要な思想の影響下にあったということでしょうか？
did not completely change the thinking of the Chinese people
中国人の考え方を完全に変えることはできなかった
That is to say, our Chinese-style dining table has its own bowls and plates
つまり、中華風の食卓には専用の椀と皿があるのです。
But there is still a public wooden spoon
しかし、まだ公共の木のスプーンがあります
Then the round dining table in the middle
そして真ん中の丸いダイニングテーブル
They just kind of have that area kind of like the line between the individual and the group
彼らには、個人とグループの間の境界線のような領域があります
stagnant forces like the conflict between national culture and liberalism
国民文化と自由主義の間の対立などの停滞する力
can speak
話せる
that thank you very much
それは本当にありがとう
Because I think you're actually continuing my question now, right?
というのは、あなたは今、私の質問を実際に続けていると思うからですよね？
and make a comparison
そして比較してみます
That means again two different cultures
それはまた 2 つの異なる文化を意味します
the different way you make them eat
食べさせる方法が違う
Does represent a different one
別のものを表します
Embracing Different Values
異なる価値観を受け入れる
can i say that
それを言ってもいいですか
Then can you put your last question in
それでは最後の質問を入れていただけますか
Ask me at the end in this context
この文脈で最後に聞いてください
what do you mean
どういう意味
can you say a little more, yes
もう少し言ってもらえますか、はい
which part did you say at the end
最後にどの部分を言いましたか
Oh that's the question you wanted to ask me
ああ、それがあなたが私に聞きたかった質問です
what to do what will you say in the end
どうしよう 結局何言うの？
i mean can i say that
つまり、それを言ってもいいですか
Yes, that is to say, the influence of that trend of thought can be
はい、つまり、その思想傾向の影響は次のとおりです。
customary when reflected in that influence
その影響を反映すると慣習的になる
Uh, I think to a very large extent
ああ、かなりの範囲でそう思います
should be visible
見えるはずです
It's pretty obvious in my story, isn't it?
私の話ではそれは明らかですよね？
as they were discussing
彼らが議論していたとき
while discussing on the one hand discussing
議論しながら、片手で議論している
How to protect hygiene from combined disease
複合疾患から衛生を守る方法
Maybe that aspect is also in the
もしかしたらそういう側面もあるかもしれない
Some people are conscious, some people are not
意識している人もいるし、意識していない人もいる
actually you are discussing
実際にあなたは議論しています
what value are you embracing
あなたはどのような価値観を大切にしていますか
What else is worth maintaining, right?
他に維持する価値のあるものは何ですか？
that's why i think so
だから私はそう思うのです
I think there are two parts to your question
あなたの質問には2つの部分があると思います
The first part is to say
最初の部分は言うことです
The Japanese way of eating
日本の食事法
It should be the way Japan eats
それが日本の食事法であるべきだ
It was only later in Japan that people ate like this, right?
日本でこのように食べるようになったのは、もっと後のことですよね？
I don't know about this
これについてはわかりません
i find it very interesting
とても興味深いと思います
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
I just mentioned one I know better, that is
私がよく知っていることについて言及しました。
Conversely
逆に
You see we were talking about individualism just now, right?
先ほど個人主義について話したことがわかりましたよね?
But the Japanese feel that
しかし日本人はそう感じている
the way they used to eat
彼らがよく食べていた方法
that everyone eats everyone
みんながみんなを食べること
Seems like everyone has a little one when eating
食事のときにみんな小さなものを持っているようです
It lacks a sense of family
家族意識が欠けている
So I don't understand what is called modern family
だから現代家族というものが理解できない
So instead they create a
そこで、代わりに、
That round table on Batatami
バタタミのあの丸テーブル
can be put away
片付けることができます
so that you can have a western-style modern family
西洋風のモダンな家族を築くために
So I just actually answered like this
だから私は実際にこのように答えました
you mean to say
あなたが言いたいのは
In fact, in terms of Western civilization
実は西洋文明で言えば、
Seems like you're not just an individualism
あなたはただの個人主義者ではないようですね
right
右
There is another one called modern family
モダンファミリーというもうひとつの家族がある
What kind of concept is HongSuiHong?
ホンスイホンとはどのようなコンセプトですか？
Then there is someone in Japan who embraces that part
そしてその部分を受け入れてくれる人が日本にいます
in this way of dining
このような食事方法で
then i don't know if i have answered your question now
それでは、今あなたの質問に答えたかどうかわかりません
that
それか
you can ask me again
もう一度聞いてもいいですか
yes
はい
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
matter of time maybe our last question
時間の問題かもしれない最後の質問
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
Then the picture I just came over becomes
すると今やって来た写真はこうなります
In fact, I also read the teacher's article
実は私も先生の記事を読みました
The article about today's actor
今日の俳優に関する記事
In fact, the teacher mentioned later that
実際、先生は後ほどこうおっしゃいました。
About the relationship between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party after 1949
1949年以降の国民党と共産党の関係について
That is to say, because of the historical relationship
つまり歴史的な関係から
So it means that the Communist Party is ruling on the earth wall of China
つまり共産党が中国の土壁を支配しているということになる
Then they are in public health
そうすれば彼らは公衆衛生の場にいる
In fact, there is a very different way
実は全く違う方法があるのです
For example, like what the teacher said just now
例えば、今先生がおっしゃったように、
is that they then become
それは彼らがそうなるということです
The so-called social disease thing
いわゆる社会病的なもの
There is one such system that happens
そういうシステムが一つあるんだ
In fact, I have also seen that they regard the matter of personal hygiene as a
実際、私はまた、彼らが個人衛生の問題を重要な問題として考えているのを見てきました。
It's just that the teacher didn't write in the article just now
ただ先生が今の記事に書いてなかっただけです
become an intellectual
知識人になる
It can be said that they are arrogant or that they are farmers from outside the cloud
傲慢とも言えるし、雲の外の農民とも言える
So instead they want to invite these intellectuals to
そこで彼らは代わりにこれらの知識人を招待したいと考えています。
For example, going down the mountain to the countryside
例えば、山を下りて田舎へ行くと、
Go to the countryside
田舎に行きます
Then say to learn from these farmers
それから、この農民から学ぶように言います
Then I also want to ask about another one like this
それから、もう一つこんなことも聞きたいのですが、
In the process of changing from individualism to collectivism
個人主義から集団主義へ変化する過程で
How have their public health policies changed?
公衆衛生政策はどのように変化しましたか?
wow you this is a big question
うわー、これは大きな質問です
This is really a very, very big problem
これは本当にとても大きな問題です
sorry
ごめん
what should i say
私は何を言えばいい
Um
えーっと
That is to say, in fact, today I
つまり、実は今日私は、
What is emphasized here is that there are some
ここで強調されているのは、いくつかの点があるということです。
pertaining to cultural values
文化的価値観に関するもの
In the example you gave
あなたが挙げた例では
a big part is to say
大きな部分は言うことです
I see what to say
言うべきことは分かりました
In fact, what I said was actually about
実際、私が言ったことは実際に次のことについてでした
The difference between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party is not only the political system
国民党と共産党の違いは政治制度だけではない
their different ideas
彼らの異なる考え
also reflected in their view
彼らの意見にも反映されています
What is an awakened person
覚醒者とは
what is hygiene worth pursuing
追求する価値のある衛生とは何ですか
are also different
も異なります
Actually, look at what we just said in the Fa lecture.
実際、法講義で私たちが今話した内容を見てください。
more or less actually you still
多かれ少なかれ、実際にはあなたはまだ
It is the introduction of a Western concept of hygiene
西洋の衛生概念の導入です
right
右
Awakened person you should
あなたがすべき覚醒者
Know to use your personal hygiene cup
個人用衛生カップの使用方法を知る
right
右
Even if you think you want to maintain
維持したいと思っていても
your original family life
あなたの本来の家族生活
You must at least cooperate with the male chopsticks and the female pool
少なくとも男性の箸と女性のプールには協力しなければなりません
In order to inevitably transmit the bacteria to other people
必然的に細菌を他の人に伝染させるため
then i just
それから私はちょうど
You said that the guidance of that article is to say
あなたは、その記事の指針は次のように述べています。
I was quite surprised to see that
それを見てかなり驚きました
That is to say, the Communist Party members in Yan'an will emphasize that
つまり延安の共産党員はこう強調するだろう。
you should not pay attention to hygiene
衛生面に気を配る必要はない
Because you paid attention to hygiene at that time
当時は衛生面に気を使っていたから
you will be out of the crowd
あなたは群衆から外れてしまいます
So this instead means that you have not awakened a transition point
つまりこれは、あなたがまだ移行点を起こしていないことを意味します
That's actually what you just asked
それは実際にあなたが今質問したことです
I find it hard to answer
答えるのは難しいと思います
It's just that I think this involves a very big problem
ただ、これは非常に大きな問題を含んでいると思います
That is to say, I think the Communist Party and the Kuomintang
つまり、共産党と国民党だと思います。
there is a very big difference
非常に大きな違いがあります
Which means they also think they embrace science
つまり、彼らも科学を受け入れていると考えているということです
but they think they can hug
でも彼らは抱きしめられると思っている
is a different science
それは異なる科学です
Science as opposed to the bourgeois West
科学とブルジョア西側の対立
It's a so-called follower of the public
いわゆる人フォローです。
A science of mass union
集団結合の科学
And this can become a very different science
そしてこれはまったく異なる科学になる可能性があります
Including their later policy on TCM as well
中医学に関するその後の方針も含めて
so because you just said
だからあなたが今言ったから
What are the different public health policies
さまざまな公衆衛生政策とは何ですか
In fact, a big one is to say
実際、大きなことは次のとおりです。
They believe they can develop a
彼らは、自分たちが開発できると信じています。
Used by more people
より多くの人に利用されている
To include the policy of TCM
中医学の方針を盛り込むには
That's actually a very big subject.
それは実際には非常に大きなテーマです。
that one and another
それともう一つ
one part is to say
一部は言うことです
Conversely, that is
逆に言えば、それは
that for example like
それは例えば
Originally, during the period of the Nationalist Party
元々は国民党時代に
Injection of smallpox vaccine
天然痘ワクチンの注射
Only a few million people at most
せいぜい数百万人だけ
1950 to 1950
1950年から1950年
The CCP has vaccinated 100 to 200 million people
中国共産党は1億人から2億人にワクチンを接種した
So in fact that becomes saying
実際、それは次のようになります
you have an unprecedented strength
あなたは前例のない強さを持っています
to get vaccinated
予防接種を受けるために
At the same time, it may be behind
同時に、遅れている可能性もあります
The issue of account control
アカウント管理の問題
That's what we see today
それが今日私たちが見ているものです
combine
結合
This should belong to Mr. Zeng
これは曾氏のものであるはずです
The question of the relationship between the political society is that
政治社会間の関係の問題は、
how do you put technology right
テクノロジーをどのように適切に活用しますか
one combined with political control
政治的統制と組み合わせたもの
a story
ストーリー
So when you just said
それであなたが今言ったとき
i have a hard time answering
答えるのに困っています
I think it's a
だと思います
very large and important
とても大きくて重要な
Important issues
重要な問題
right
右
as we end today's
今日を終えるにあたり
prior to this knowledge
この知識の前に
allow me 30 seconds
30秒待ってください
a little advance notice
少し事前のお知らせ
our next speech
私たちの次のスピーチ
when is our next speech
私たちの次のスピーチはいつですか
it was on april 26
4月26日でした
same time
同一個時間
7:00 to 8:30
7:00～8:30
the same place
同じ場所
then we are
それなら私たちは
In memory of former Dean Gu
元グー学部長を偲んで
Then we invited
それから私たちは招待しました
Taipei Medical University
台北医科大学
Chair Professor Academician Liu Fang
議長教授 学術研究員 Liu Fang
he came to speak for us
彼は私たちのために話をするために来た
From housing to longevity
住まいから長寿へ
unlock
ロックを解除する
common mechanism
共通の仕組み
Then if this is because of this series of this in our middle school
では、これが私たちの中学校での一連の出来事のせいだとしたら、
Dean Gu's
ディーン・グー
This is a test of fact
これは事実のテストです
Everyone took the initiative to accept and saw that there are really good ones.
誰もが率先して受け入れ、本当に良いものがあることに気づきました。
The level we have invited are all very outstanding and excellent scholars
私たちが招待したレベルは皆、非常に優秀で優秀な学者です
So you are welcome to continue to participate
ですので、引き続きご参加いただけますと幸いです
So in the end, shall we give the warmest applause
それでは最後に温かい拍手を送りましょうか
Thank you again for our speakers today
本日も講演者に感謝します
very good very wonderful speech
とても良い、とても素晴らしいスピーチ
Thank you, Mr. Lei, Director Lei.
レイ監督、レイさん、ありがとうございました。
Thank you also to the family of President Wang Gu
王九大統領のご家族にも感謝します。
Ms. Zhang
張さん
Of course, thank you very much for your participation.
もちろん、ご参加いただき誠にありがとうございました。
Thank you all, that concludes our lecture today.
皆さん、ありがとうございました。今日の講義はこれで終わります。
Thank you for your participation
ご参加ありがとうございます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you for your participation today
本日はご参加いただきありがとうございました
The first implementation don't forget to take our student belongings
初回実施時は学生の持ち物を忘れずに持っていきましょう
so interesting
興味深い
Gathering at school
学校での集まり